(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T00:57:19.641305",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
よいしょ
There we go.
この日が来ちまったなぁ
Well, this day has finally come.
こんなにも拡大して巨大な組織になった桐生会。
The Kiryu-kai has grown so much into a massive organization.
別れるのは惜しいですが、皆さんは私の心の中で生きていくんだからな、兄弟達よ！
It's sad to part ways, but you'll all live on in my heart, my brothers!
今日は私の卒業ライブということで、
Today is my graduation live, so...
実はお世話になりましたホロライブの仲間たちが、この事務所に遊びに来てくれることになりました！
Actually, my fellow Hololive friends who've taken care of me are coming to visit this office!
とってもね、お別れするのは寂しいですけど、
I'm very sad to say goodbye, but...
この卒業最後の最後この場で、皆さんとたくさん笑顔でお話ししてお別れをしたいと思います！
at this very last moment of my graduation, I want to talk with everyone with lots of smiles and say goodbye!
それでは先輩方から皆さんにお話を聞いていきたいと思います。
So, I'd like to hear from my seniors first.
0期生
[0th Generation]
では、今日この時間からですね、
Okay! Starting with this segment,
まあ先輩方ですとかね、他のホロライブメンバーにお話をお伺いしたいと思いまして、
I've invited the other hololive members to join me for a final chat.
今日なんと、あのスーパー先輩方に、来ていただきました！
And I'm pleased to announce that the OGs of the OGs are here with me today!
たーだ！
Ta-dah!
やったー！
Yay!
うぉー！わー！
Whoo-hoo!
いやもう先輩中の先輩方ですからね、ちょっと緊張しちゃうんですけれど、
I'm practically a rookie next to you guys. It's making me kinda nervous.
あの今日は少しあの、私卒業をするということで、
So today, since I'll be graduating, I wanted to...
やだよ！やだ！やだ！
Don't go! Please stay!
お話を、えっと聞きたいと、思いまして！
I wanted to take this opportunity to speak with you all.
あの、まあ、
So, well...
私のね、第一印象なんかちょっとそういうところから聞いていきたいななんて思っているんですけれども
I thought I'd start with your first impressions of me.
先輩方、え、どうでしょうか？
Well, what were they?
おっ？
Oh?
誰から、ど、どなたそわ、という人を挙手になさってください。どうぞ！
Who wants to go first? Raise your hand! Come on! Hands up!
はいはいはいはい！はいはい！さ、さくらみこ、どうぞ！
Me! Me! Me! Very well, Sakura Miko. Right!
え、まずね、みこの、会長への、こう、第一印象と言えば、やっぱり、朝ココなんですよね。
One of my earliest memories of the Chairman has got to be Morning Coco. Right, of course!
うん、そうそう、そうそう、いや、本当にそう。
Morning Coco was just like...
朝ココは本当にね、え、朝に配信するのっていうね、驚きとともに、めちゃくちゃね、こう作り込んでたりとか、のぶっ飛ばんでたりとか
First, I was so surprised that you'd do a morning stream. Plus, the production values were high and the subject matter so insane... Uh-huh.
もう、あるんだけど、やっぱり、あの、その中で、あ、ネオは真面目なんだなとか、あ、しっかりしてんなっていうところがね、すごい伝わった、もう、会長のよさが100%伝わったいい番組だったなって
But most of all, it made me realize how dedicated and responsible you were at heart. I think it was a great show that showcased everything great about you.
思ってね。
Agreed!
そう。わかれー！そう。
Yeah, totally!
結構、なんか初配信から、パンチが効いてたと思うんだけど。
You were always pushing boundaries, even from your debut stream.
本当ですか？
You think so?
本当。なんか誰もやってないことやってるって感じだったね。
Yeah! You were doing things no one had ever done before.
私が初配信見てすげえ爆笑したのは、えっと、なんか
What really cracked me up during your debut stream was the part where you were like...
あの、お尻が大きすぎてビルを潰しちゃったんですみたいなこと
your butt was so big, you crushed a building.
スマッシュ！そうそう、そうそう、潰しちゃったからね、何言ってるんだろうと思ってすごい面白くて
Smash! Yeah, that's right. It was so out of left field that I totally cracked up.
すごい面白い子来たなと思ってて、ねえ、なんか、そらちゃんとかどう思った初配信見て。
I thought that this new girl's a riot! So, what did you think of her debut, Sora-chan?
気になる。なんか、いろんな意味で大きいなって思ったのが最初の印象で
Ooh, I wanna know! Well, my first impression was, she's really big in a lot of ways. Not only is she tall...
背も大きいし、デカいです。
I'm big, all right! Right, she's really big...
まあ、大きいし、ねえ、
and on top of that, she's a dragon!
で、なおかつドラゴンっていうことで、なんかね、すっごい面白い子が来たなと思ったし、やっぱり、なんか今までとは違って新しいなと思ったのは、やっぱ、なんか、なんかネイティブな英語が達者すぎて
So she really caught my attention. But most of all, the one thing we'd never seen before was her perfect, native English.
確かに！確かに、そらちゃん。
That's for sure! That's true.
まあ、すごいなって思ったイメージがすごい強かった。
All in all, I was just really impressed. Yeah. That's right.
いや、やっぱね、0期生って、あんまり絡む機会がここちなかったと思うんだけど
So Cocochi, you didn't get as many chances to interact with Gen 0. Like, did you ever get a chance to talk to AZKi-chan?
あ、なんかあずきちゃんとかとはどうだった？なんか結構絡みとかは。
Oh, but we did a collab together, right?
いや、あんなのも、あずき先輩ともね、あの二人でコラボもさせてもらったしね。
That's right!
あのね、僕会長の、あのシャイニースマリストーリーあるじゃないですか。あれの英訳の歌詞がめちゃくちゃすごい感動して
See, I was really moved when I heard Chairman Coco's English lyrics for "Shiny Smily Story." So I got in touch and said
なんかその、そうそう、その、あの歌詞を、なんかあずきもお貸ししてくださいて1回連絡をして、そしたらもう快く歌詞をすぐさま送ってきてくれて、なんか、そのエピソードとか忘れられないです。
I wanted to sing those lyrics, too. And without a moment's hesitation, she sent them to me. I still remember that fondly.
私もすごく嬉しかったんですよ、あの、あの英語のやつがすごい素敵だから、歌いたいなって言ってくださいまして。
I was also really flattered to hear from you! I couldn't believe you liked the English version so much that you wanted to sing it.
ええ！そ、まさかね、あずき先輩がね、あの配信で歌ってくださるとは思わず、皆さん聞きましたか？
I was like, "What?!" I never thought that the AZKi-senpai would sing my lyrics on stream. Have you guys listened to it?
いや最高っすよ、あれ。私がね、あの、ま、卒業していなくなっても、ぜひ、あの英語の、英語の歌詞をぜひ歌っていただけたらなんて
It slaps. I hope you guys will keep on singing those lyrics even after I'm gone.
歌うよ！歌うよ！ coco！
We will. Of course, we'll sing it!
お願いします！うわあ！
Please do!
皆さんね、本当に、結構、あの、ま、雲の上の存在というか、私にとっては、結構、あの先輩オブ先輩じゃないですか。
To me, it always felt like you guys were in a class of your own. I mean, you're the OGs, after all.
なんかちょっと、かなり、あの、なんていうか、敬うレベルが高かったんで、なかなかね、あの自分からどんどんいけないというところが、正直あったんですけど
I was so in awe of you guys that it was honestly hard for me to approach you.
それでもね、先輩方から関係なくね、ガンガン絡みに来てくれたんで、本当にそこはね、今でもとっても感謝しております。
But you guys were so proactive about approaching me. To this day, I'm truly grateful for that.
うん。
Gosh, I'm so touched.
いやあ、嬉しいよ！なんか、なんかみこ、こんなに敬ってもらうこと初めてだからさ、そんな大先輩とか言われたら
I've never had someone look up to me like that. Calling me an OG and all...
すいません、今の話の中のはみこ先輩は含まれてないですね。
It makes me so happy... You're the only one who sees me that way, Chairman! Oh, I should clarify. What I said earlier doesn't include you, Miko-senpai.
なんでだよ！みこじゃねえって何だよ！みこ先輩はなんかぐちゃぐちゃに、なんかいじっていい人みたいになってます。すいません！
Wait, why?! How come?! Miko-senpai, you're just... I have no qualms about teasing you mercilessly, Miko-senpai. My apologies.
なんでだよ！それはそう！それはそうじゃねえよ！それはそうやね。
Why?! No doubt about it. Have some doubt! But it's true.
なんか、3D来たときも、だいぶインパクトが、あったイメージがあるロボコは。なんか首が、そう、首くくくくくってやってたりね。
And I really remember your 3D debut leaving a big impression on me. Your neck was like "bam, bam, bam."
そう、腰も、腰もくくくくくってやってたりね。そう、いや、動き、動きすごすぎ。3Dの中で一番やばいよ、その動きが。これができなくなるっていうのはね、なので今のうちに皆さん好きなだけ見といてください。
And your hips were like "bam, bam, bam" as well. Yeah. Why're you so good at that? Those moves are just too much! You're such an entertainer! I won't be able to do this anymore, so please enjoy it now while you still can!
みこさん本当あの私とね、あの積極的に絡んでいただいて
So, I wanted to say thank you to all of you
全然ね本当、あの、私が勝手にね、絡みにくいと思って、いただけで、全然皆さんすごく絡みやすくて本当に、本当はい、あの、感謝して
for approaching me so proactively. Maybe I just kind of assumed that you were all hard to approach, but you're all actually really easy to talk to and I'm so thankful for that!
こちらこそこちらこそこちら、
No, thank you!
こちらこそもう本当に。
Thank you! But like, Coco, Thank you so much!
でもね、会長はさ、あのミコたちのことそうやって言ってくれるけど、卒業してもやっぱりね本当にホロライブにとってすごく大きな存在だったし
you say all that about us, but you're still going to be a very important part of hololive even after graduating.
私、だからね、ウチらも育成してくれた人だってミコは思っとるから会長もすごいすごいレジェンダリーな会長だよ！
I feel like you've helped make hololive what it is today, so you're a super legendary Chairman yourself.
やった！
Yay!
やったよ！もう会長はレジェンド、レジェンドや。レジェンドだよ。すごいと、もうマジで
The Chairman is legendary! You're a legend! Yeah, you really are amazing.
伝説に伝説って言われちゃったんですけど、これいいんですか？こんな、こんな嬉しいこと言われちゃって。
The legends are telling me that I'm a legend... Is it really okay to... accept this praise?
なんか、伝説になってけ。伝説になってけ。
Aw, me? A legend? You're making me blush. Accept your legendary status.
皆さん本当に今日はあの、あの私のために来ていただいて本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you, everyone, for joining me today. Thank you so much!
あの、本当最後、最後のって言うのは寂しいですけど
It was our pleasure. It's that this is going to be our last time together,
どうか私のこと忘れないでください！
but please don't forget about me!
やめてくれ、忘れないよ！
As if we could ever forget you!
焼肉行こう！
Let's go for barbecue sometime!
いつでも行きましょう！
Yeah, let's go whenever you want!
やめてもホロライブの一員ですから！
Even if you leave, you'll still be a member of hololive forever!
そうだよ！本当だよ！本当にありがとうございます！
Exactly! Yeah, that's right! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you!
こちらスーパー先輩方でした！ありがとうございました！
Give it up for the OGs of the OGs. Thank you so much!
すうう！
Thank you!
では、次は1期生の先輩方に来ていただきました！1期生の大先輩方、
Our next guests are the members of 1st Generation! The OG generation!
ようこそ私の事務所へ来ていただきました！ありがとうございます！やった！
Welcome to my HQ! Thanks for coming! Yay!
やったー！お邪魔しまーす！
Yay! Thanks for having us!
なんだここ、面接会場かここ。すごい圧迫面接。
What is this, an interview room? It sure is!
どうして、面接？キリュウカに受かりたいんですかね？
So, why did you apply to the Kiryu Group?
あ、あ、俺強くなくたくて
'Cause I'm tired of being a weakling, Boss!
いや、逆じゃないですか？私たちが面接されてるのではないか、これ？
Actually, we've got it backwards. I'm the one undergoing a stress interview, here.
あ、じゃあ、私たち面接官ってことですかね？
That's true! So that makes us the interviewers? We're interviewers!
今日は私の卒業ライブということで、まあね、まあ最後にね、こうしてお話しできる、まあ、皆さんの前でね、最後でお話できる機会ですので、
So, today's my graduation concert and my last chance to talk to you guys, at least publicly.
あの、せっかくですからね、あの私の第一印象でしたりとか、まあそういう、まあ思い出とかをちょっと語る時間を取ろうかと思いまして、
So I was hoping to ask about your first impressions of me and memories with me and stuff.
そういうの、あの、いいですか先輩方、語ってくれても。
Would that be okay with you guys? Yeah, of course!
じゃあ、まず、ここちの第一印象！第一印象。
Okay, first impressions of Cocochi!
第一印象。
First impressions?
まぁね、やべえのが来たなっていう感じ。
"Loose cannon," I guess. "Oh boy, we got a real feisty one."
やべえ！
Loose cannon?!
あの第一印象だけなら見た目でまずでっけぇってなってくるね。うん。でっかいなっていう
Well, my first thought when I saw was, "Huge!" She really is huge. Like wow, she's so tall.
そうそうそう。何もかもデカかったよね。本当にあの、大物が来たなって感じがね。
Everything about you was huge. Yeah, everything about you. I knew you'd do big things, too.
あとさ、でもさ、デビュー配信のときさ、割と可愛いこう絵のタッチの、こうドラゴンがホロライブ事務所に落ちてきてっていう
But remember her debut stream? With the dragon, in that cute art style, crashing into the hololive office.
あ、そうなんだよ。そうそう。だから可愛い感じの子なのかなって思って、見たらフタ開けたらFワード飛び交うようなね、クソザコリバーツが、強すぎて草
Oh yeah! That's right! The video was cute. So I was expecting someone girly. But what I found was an F-bomb-dropping, gunslinging dragon.
いや絶対ここちゃんから学んだ、そういうなんかね、単語いっぱいあるよ。あるあるよ。
I definitely learned a lot of that sort of vocabulary from you! Tons!
うん、私も。ねえ、なんか、「ママ」とか。ね、「ママ」とか。
Me too! Right? Like "mother..." you know.
学んでしまったよ、本当。
It was quite the education.
まあ、皆さ、あの、こここ、じゃあ、あの皆さん第一印象は割と清楚な、ドラゴンなのに
So, basically, your first impression of me was a pure dragon? Uh, were you even listening?
何も聞いてねえじゃねえかお前！
What are you talking about?
まつり先輩に言われたくないんですけど。いや、私は清楚ですよ。
I don't want to hear that from you, Matsuri-senpai! Well I am pure.
もうここはね、まつりラインをね、初めて越えた女やからね。
You were the first one to cross the "Matsuri Line."
確かに。まつり先輩にそんな風に認められたら、さしずめ
That's true. That's an honor coming from you, Matsuri-senpai!
すいませんでした。すいません。ちょっと失礼いたしました。
It's the truth. Terribly sorry about earlier.
まあ、あの、第一印象からね、あの1年、1年何ヶ月ぐらい、あの
So it's been about a year and seven months since those first impressions.
経ちまして どうですか？ 私の今 あの… 今の印象は だいぶ変わりましたかね？
So it's been about a year and seven months since those first impressions. I imagine your impressions of me have changed a lot?
あ でも あれじゃない？ なんか その はちゃめちゃだけど すごいなれよりも真面目なイメージはある
Well, I still think you're crazy, but you're also one of the most responsible people I know.
頼れるお姉ちゃんって感じがする！
Like a reliable big sister!
え！？
Yeah!
いや待って、あの子供ドラゴンなんで、あの、も、こ、こ、
I'm still just a kid dragon! I mean...
子供はそんなこと言わないの！
Kids don't talk like you do!
なんちゃっての！
Exactly!
子供だぞ！子供だと！
A kid? Yeah, right!
いや、ま、ドラゴン界の子供かもしれないけどさ！
Well, maybe she's a kid by dragon standards. She's shaking her hips!
そうだよ！
Right!
うちらイブではお姉ちゃんだよ！お姉ちゃんだよ！
But you're a big sister in hololive! You're an older sister!
お姉ちゃん！ うん、まあ、ま、でも、皆さん、私にとって皆さんは頼れるお姉ちゃんであり先輩なんで、たくさん、あの、活動してる間たくさん、あの、頼らせていただいた、本当にありがとうございます！
A big sister?! Well, okay... To me, you guys are my reliable big sisters. I look up to you. You were there for me during my time here. Thank you so much!
こちらこそ！ありがとうございました！
It was our pleasure! Thank you! Our pleasure!
こちらこそ、いつもいろんなものをね、くれてますから。
You've given us so much.
ろ、ろ、最後の最後まで、最後の最後まで、もう最後まで不放送に、放送画面にうんち乗っけてたからな！
I had poop on my stream until the very end, you know!
いや、ま、約束なんでね、あの、
Well, that was the agreement! Ah, crap!
くそ！くそだけにって？
Literally crap, right? That's what was on your stream.
くそだけに、くそ！くそだけに、くそ！くそだけに！
Crap indeed! Crap only!
おー！あ、あれみんなにもあげるよ、あの、うんち
I'll gladly share the poop with you guys. I'll give some poop to everyone too.
思い出にさ、思い出の、あの、アホ毛の代わりに付けとこうかな。
Maybe I'll wear it on my head, as a memento, instead of my ahoge. Ew, stinky-head!
髪飾りの代わりに付けとこうかな。
Maybe I'll replace my hairpin with it.
待って待って！きたないです！アイドルじゃなくなっちゃう！
Stop! This is getting filthy! The OGs are gonna lose their idol cred!
皆さん、あの、私との思い出もね、たくさん作りましたけど、
Well, you've all made lots of memories with me.
なんかですごく印象に残ってることとか、ありますか？
Is there anything that sticks out in your mind?
ありますか？
Is there?
めちゃくちゃあるね！最初の絡みはARKだったかな、メル。あ、
Well, I first interacted with you via ARK. Yeah, ARK!
そうね、ARK！困ってたら助けに来てくれて、すごく優しい子だな、って思った。
When I was in trouble, you came to rescue me. You were so kind.
たくさん一緒にARKで遊びましたね！ うん、うん。
We sure had lots of fun in ARK together. Yeah.
といえば、ココちゃんでね、大量のうん、またうんが、
Speaking of ARK, Coco-chan gave me a ton of poo...
ちょっと待て待て、思い出それじゃないでしょ！私1年半ずっと頑張って活動してきて最後の思い出うんこって、こんなことないですよ！
Are all these memories about poo?! Why is it all about poo?! After all I've done in this year and a half, your final memories are of poo?! That can't be right!
でも、めちゃくちゃね、面白いゲームを教えてもらって、みんなでね、できてるのがすごい楽しいから、これからもね、やっていきたいなって思ってるよ。
But you introduced us to an awesome game that's so much fun to play together, so I plan to keep playing.
そう、いっぱい遊んでるもんね、アキローズね。まだまだやりたいこといっぱいあるからね。みんなでたくさん一緒に遊んで、
Gosh! You got really addicted, AkiRose. I still have a lot left to do in that game. We got to play a lot together,
あの、ハチャマもね、結構2人でコラボとかたくさんさせてもらいましたけど、
and I teamed up a lot with Haachama, in particular.
あの、これからね、ホロライブを卒業して、オージになっても、ぜひ、あの、まあ、視聴者の皆さんのちょっと見えないところになっちゃいますけど、お友達として仲良くして、いただけますか？
After I graduate hololive and become an alumna, it'll have to be out of the viewers' sight, but will you still be friends with me?
もう絶対焼肉行く行こうな！
You betcha! Let's get barbecue together!
焼肉行こう！一緒に行こう！嬉しい！やる！やった！やったー！
Yeah, let's! Yay!
先輩、あの、皆さん、焼肉奢ってください。お願いします！
As kind, senior members, you'll be paying, right?
世界一のスパチャでろが！奢ってくれよ！
Says the top Super Chated in the world! Yeah! You pay!
奢ってくれよ！卒業したら、あの無職になっちゃうんで、あの無職、無職、無職、オッケー！
W-Well, I'll be unemployed after I graduate... Please, I'm unemployed! Well, I guess we'll have to, then.
最後まで楽しくしてくれてありがとうございます！こちら今日のきのために駆けつけてくれた1期生の先輩方でした！
Thanks for the fun times, including today! That was 1st Generation, who were kind enough to join me today!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
では、え、次は2期生の先輩方がこちらの事務局に来て、え、くれました！先輩！
Okay! Our next guests are the members of 2nd Generation, right here in my HQ! Hello!
イェーイ！
Yay!
お邪魔します。ようこそ私の、え、卒業ライブへ。
Thanks for having us. Welcome to my graduation concert.
え、あの、今日でね、私はホロライブをね、まあ、卒業生、オージという形にさせていただくのですけれども、
Today, I'm graduating from hololive and becoming a former member, an alumna.
先輩方1年と、え、7ヶ月ぐらい、お世話になりました！
Thank you for everything this past year and, uh, seven-or-so months!
はい、ココちゃん、ありがとうございました！
Coco-chan! Thank you too! Thank you for everything. Chairman!
今日はですね、あのちょっと第一印象ですとか、
So I was hoping to ask about your first impressions of me,
まあいろいろこの、短い期間ですけど、会ったこととかを少しお話しできればと思いまして、
any memories you made with me during this short period of time and stuff.
先輩方、何か、
Would you like to talk about anything?
思い出とか、私の、まあ第一印象と今の違いとか、ありますか？
Or, like, has your impression of me changed since we first met?
いやね、会長はね、もうやっぱりさ、会長と言えばARKみたいなとこあるじゃん。
Well, we can't talk about you without bringing up ARK, can we?
ね、マジでブームだったよね、完全に。
It was really booming back then.
めっちゃ流行ってた！みんなやってたよね！
Everyone was playing it! It was all the rage.
ね、ま、会長との思い出って言うと、やっぱり、なんか配信では乗ってなかったんだけど、あのそのなんかボス戦の準備、そんときにね、会長がなんかすごいねいろんなことを語ってくれて、まあデビューしたけどどう？みたいな感じで聞いてたら、
As for memories made with you, it wasn't on stream, but when preparing for some boss raid, we talked a lot, even though you just debuted. When I asked her how things were going, she was like,
会長がね、なんか、あの、もっと、あのVTuberっていう文化、ホロライブをもっとみんなに知ってほしいみたいな、もっと世界中の人に知ってほしいみたいなこと言ってて、
"I want people to learn about hololive and VTuber culture! I want people all around the world to get to know them!"
なんか、その時からそういうさ、こう大きな夢を持ってるってことすごいし、
It was amazing that she had such a big dream so soon after debuting.
実際ね、やっぱり、会長はさ、もう言い切れないほどのものを残してる人だなあって思って、
And indeed, she's left an indescribable mark on this whole sphere. She's really amazing, no doubt.
作業しながらやってたんですけど、そこから作業の机にあるものから伝わった、ずっと地面を泳ぎながらずっとやってた。
I was just goofing off, playing on the floor while working on something.
めっちゃ楽しかったよね、いろんな思い出がありますよ。
Yeah, it was! I have tons of memories from those times.
どうですか、他にも皆さんありますか？
Anything else, anyone?
ちょ、初配信を見たときは、本当に日本語めっちゃ頑張ってて、
I noticed during your debut stream that you were really making an effort to speak Japanese.
頑張ってる中で見えるこの、やばい部分。やばい部分見えて
But behind that effort, your wild nature was clear for all to see. It was in plain sight.
めちゃめちゃ頑張ってって思ったけど、「ん？」って思うこともちょっとあって、そこがね、すごいねいい意味でやばくて面白かったんだけど、
I knew you were doing your best, but also was like, "Uhh..." That was crazy in a good way, and I thought it was funny.
二人でスーバーバニーマンっていうゲームを
We also played Super Bunny Man together.
そうなんだよね、ウサギのゲームをねやったね！
Oh right, you did! We did indeed! That bunny game...
やったときに本当におもしろすぎて、初めて漏らすかと思って。
It was so funny that, for the first time in my life, I thought I was gonna wet myself.
やめなさい！アイドルだろ！
Cut it out! You're an idol!
漏らすかと思って。いや、こんな経験は初めてでした。本当に楽しかった。
It was so funny I thought I was gonna wet myself. I've never experienced that before. It was really fun.
楽しかったよねえ、面白かった。
It was! It was indeed. It was fun.
あやめ先輩とは実はね、あの、中では結構絡みがね、残念ながら少なかったんじゃないかなって。
Unfortunately, me and Ayame-senpai haven't interacted much, compared to the others here.
そうなんですよ。全然ね、もっとね、いろんなこと、もっとね、あの、あそびたかったんですけどね。
That's right... Unfortunately. But from now on... That's quite unusual. I wanted to hang out.
でも、本当一つ謝りたくて。ココちゃんに、あの、朝ココに出てくれませんかっていうお話を、いただいたときがあって。
Allow me to apologize for something here. Coco-chan asked me once if I'd like to appear in Morning Coco.
結構前の話なんですけど、「いいよいいよ」みたいな感じで、ちょっと返していたんですけど、
That was around a year ago, right? I replied like, "Sure!"
あの提出した気持ちになっていて、全く連絡を返せていなかったっていう事件がありまして。
But then I mistakenly thought I did my work and submitted it, while in truth I'd ended up ghosting her!
本当にごめんなさい！
I'm really sorry about that!
1年間ずっと、送った気持ちになっていて、世の中には、で、あれ？
You were worried about it for a whole year? I thought I sent it, but then...
朝ココ出た？あれ？あれ消された？
"Wait, I'm not on Morning Coco..." "Wait, where are the messages?"
しかもこのタイミングでかみんぐあうとするんだよ。本当にごめんなさいもう！
You're spilling the beans now? I'm really sorry!
本当にごめんなさいもう！
I'm really sorry!
あの、あれは別に強制とかじゃないですから。あの、本当に暇な方でって感じでやってたんで。
Don't worry, I wasn't forcing anyone. Just asking whoever was free to do it.
でも、本当に、あの、あのね、もっと絡む時間できれば欲しかったなっていうのは、
But yeah, I wish I'd spent more time interacting with you.
ちょっとココ残っているところの一つありますね。
Yeah... That's one of the things I regret.
心残りです、本当に。でも、卒業した後もぜひプライベートでも、あの、ぜひ遊んでくだせえよ！
I really regret it too. But let's hang out after I graduate!
ぜひ遊びましょう！ありがとうございました。
For sure, let's do it! I'll be waiting! Thank you!
チョコせんせー！せんせー！……動きがなんか変な動きだな。
Choco-sensei... Sensei... What's with those moves?
いやもう、ココ様はさ、なんかもう最初の印象なんかもう、話してる言葉はガチでさ、なんかもう「ココ語」みたいな感じでさ、
Oh, Coco-sama... If we talk first impression... Your speech style was really something like... Coconese.
ココ語作ってると思って、「ゲボカワドラゴン」とかもそうやって言うしさ、いろいろやばい奴だなとか思いつつ
I thought that you are just creating your own language there. Stuff like "Gebokawa Dragon." I just couldn't stop thinking that you were a weird one.
そう。で、なんか第1ARKブームがあって、その時チョコさんさ、ARKのこと全然わかんなくてさ。あの、ああなんかみんなやってんだなみたいな感じだったんだけど、
Yeah. Then the first ARK boom happened. I had no idea about it before. I just casually tried it seeing how everyone else was playing it.
なんか第2波でちょっとやってみたら、いやもう、ガチハマりしちゃってさ。
But when I gave it a real go during the second wave, I got really addicted to it.
やった！めっちゃハマりになった。めちゃめちゃハマってるもんね。
You really did! So you've noticed!
そう。なんか一緒にご飯行ってもさ、なんか、いや、ARKがさ、みたいな話ししてさ。どんだけハマってんだよ。
Yeah. Even when we went to eat out together, I was like, "So, about ARK..." You could only talk about ARK!
帰ってARKやんなきゃな、ちょっと帰ってきましたからね。
Just how addicted were you? She even bounced early, saying she had to go home and play ARK.
やばいな
Wow, yikes.
たくさん、せんせい、ARK一緒に遊んでくれて本当によかったです、せんせい！
Thank you for playing lots of ARK with me, Sensei!
いや、こちらこそありがとうございます！
Thank you too!
配信上では、逆にそんなに絡んだことないかもしれない
To start off... I think we haven't interacted with each other on streams.
そうです、ね、確かに！
You... are right! That's true!
なんか意外とね、なんかめちゃくちゃ仲良しすぎた
That's quite unexpected. We spent too much time hanging out off-stream!
なんか、しれっと会長の家で行われるパーティとかには、しれっと毎回いたりする
I just nonchalantly waltz into her house if there's a party or something.
そう、しれっとすばる先輩ほぼいるんすよね
Yeah, you're just... there all the time.
そうそう、なんか行って、でなんか、あの、いつもここちゃんが、なんか、すばるぱいせん、どの飲み物にしますか？いっぱいありますよって言って飲み物をね毎回出してくれたりとか
Yeah, I always barge in, and Coco-chan is always like, "Subaru-paisen, whatcha want to drink? I have tons of drinks!" She always treats me drinks like that.
ここちゃんが、そのたこパで、オリーブオイルを重ねがけするっていう文化を
At her takoyaki parties, there's a tradition to add olive oil...
オリーブオイル！？
Olive oil?!
そうなんだよ！たこ焼きをかりかりにするんすよ
Yeah! People do that? They become crunchy!
えー！？
Huh?
めちゃめちゃ美味しくて、すばる、なんかそれ以降ホロライブメンバーとのたこパの時は毎回それしてるからホロライブメンバーみんなオリーブオイルかけるようになってて
It was so good, ever since then, I always use olive oil at takoyaki parties with other members. And now everyone in hololive likes olive oil on their takoyaki.
だからもう卒業した後もね絶対ねまたたこパ開いてください、遊びに行くわ
So please hold more takoyaki parties even after you graduate. I'll drop by.
ぜひ行きます、ぜひ行きたい！
I surely will! I wanna drop by too!
次はね、2期生の皆さんで遊びに来てくださいよ
All of you 2nd Gens come hang out sometime!
あ、そうなのね、みんなで行きます。たこ焼きみんなで行くの、焼くのは任せてほしいんで、カリカリに
Right! Nice idea! Takoyaki! Let's do it! Leave the grilling to me! I'll make 'em nice and crunchy!
ありがとうございます！今日はみんなあの来ていただいて本当にありがとうございます！ぜひ卒業後もね
Thank you! Thank you all a lot for coming today! Even after I graduate...
卒業してからもね、仲良くでいてください！はい、ありがとうございましたー！
I hope we can remain on good terms! Thank you! Of course! Bye-bye!
See ya! Bye-bye! またねー！こーこちゃん好き！
See ya! ... Luv ya, Coco!
それでは、えー次は、ホロライブゲーマーズの先輩方に来ていただきましたー！先輩！
So our next guests are the members of hololive Gamers! Hello!
やーい！わーい！
Yay!
なんか、なんか変な奴いるの？
There's some weird one mixed in.
え？角松いない？
What? There's a kadomatsu.
ほんとだ！お前らのことなんだよ！
Ah, you're right! We're talking about you!
え？あれ？間違えちゃったこと
Wh-Huh? I thought this was a good idea. Was it not appropriate?
これめちゃくちゃ浮いてるね
You stick out like a sore thumb!
私間違えちゃったよこれ。やめてよ、気持ち悪い
I might've chosen the wrong outfit for this. Stop it! That's creepy!
きゅうちゃんだね、ここちゃん。こーれはなにか、いいんですか？
Coco-chan, that's creepy! This is quite strange. Is it?
でもね、ちょっとあの、今から脱げないのよ、これ
But, y'know... I can't take this off anymore.
あ、脱げないんだ？あ、そうなんだー。じゃ、このまま行くしかないね。申し訳ないですけど
You can't? I see... Yeah. We'll just have to continue like this. I apologize for the trouble.
いや、今日はですね、あの、皆さんに来ていただきまして、ま、視聴者の皆さんの前でね、こうやって、あの、お話しするっていうのが最後っていう意味になっちゃうので
I had you all come over today for one final conversation in front of the viewers. This'll be the last time they get to see us talking.
うーん、見せつけたい、見せつけたい！あ、見せつけていきます！見せつけたいのか？
I wish we could show 'em more! Wanna keep showing off our interactions? You want to feel smug, huh?
あのね、ちょっと今までのなんか、キルココの、あの、思い出ですとか、あの、印象的だったことですとか、なんかあったら、まあ、まあ、教えてくれたっていいんですよ
I see. Well, if you have any memories with me or anything that had an impact on you that you want to share, you can do that.
私、角松、角松はやっぱり、角松先輩
I, Ms. Kadomatsu... Kadomatsu-senpai.
朝ココがすごい印象的で
For me... Morning Coco was the most memorable thing.
あの、裏社会講座とかね、すごいね
Ah, yeah. The underworld lessons segment, in particular... It helped, right?
タメになったよね！タメになったんだよ！タメになったから、ちょっと、半分以上忘れちゃってるけど
Yeah, it was so useful. It actually helped. Though I've forgotten like half of what I learned...
でも、すごい楽しかった、楽しかったし、なんか、本当に協力してもらえて
It was really fun, and I was happy I could have you help-
協力してもらえるって？協力してもらったのは、あの、角松先輩ですよ！協力していただいたのは、先輩
Have you help? You were the one who helped me, Kadomatsu-senpai! You were the one helping me!
協力、協力させてもらって、本当にね、楽しかったの！
It was fun being able to help you! You were the one helping me! Yeah. Thanks. No, thank you so much.
先輩本当にありがとうございます、先輩がね
No, thank you. I like...
こちらこそ。あのー、結構ね、あの、あの、先輩、あの、裏社会講座で、もう、コーナー、私が勝手にね、人のコーナーを勝てにつくるっていうのをもうやっちゃって。や、もうとめちゃめちゃね、面白かったの！台本もね、全部ね、作ってくれたんだよね
I made her an underworld lessons segment without asking her. It was really fun. She wrote all the scripts for me.
あ、そうなんだ。めちゃめちゃすごい！
Oh, I didn't know that. That's amazing. That's impressive. Isn't it?
ううん。もう撮るだけよ、こっちは！撮るだけでもめんどくさいね
I only had to record. Recording is a pain too.
今思ったらね、結構あの、先輩方にね、めんどくさいことさしてたなって、あの、よくそんな新人ココごときで、あの、そんなことできたなって
Looking back, I made you all do some pain-in-the-ass things. I'm wondering how I did that as a newbie. It's actually pretty shocking now.
いやあ、もうこれからも手伝うよ、裏社会講座。いいですか？やるんかい！これからも
I'll help you with your underworld lessons in the future too. Really? You're gonna keep helping?!
あの あの 皆さんに見えないところでね
We'll be holding more underworld lessons
視聴者のみなさんに 見えない裏の男でね 裏社会
where the viewers can't see.
講座もう講座 平講座に そしてね
Let's hold lessons.
やりましょう やりましょう
Yeah. The true lessons.
のね コロネにね 直接ってことね
Giving Korone direct lessons, huh?
母さん
Let's do it!
やりましょう やりましょう
Mio-sha, how about you?
うちはね
As for me...
一番の思い出は なんかデビューして まだそんなに経ってない時に
My most memorable moment was, not long after Coco's debut,
なんかその ホロライブ全体で 釣り大会をやったときあったでしょ
like... we held a fishing competition for all hololive members.
あったあった
We did.
あったね
Yeah.
あの時さ めっちゃくちゃさ 人さ あんなに集まると思わないぐらい めちゃくちゃ人集まったじゃん ホロライブメンバー
We got so many members together back then. We didn't think we'd have that many people!
で それでここちゃんは 参加したいけどできないみたいな感じになっちゃってて
And Coco-chan wanted to participate too, but couldn't. Yeah.
でも当日 なんかかんないけど パッションだけで なんかやってくれたみたいな
But on the day of the competition, she found a way to join in through sheer passion.
あったあった そういうの 釣ってくれたことあった
Yeah, that happened...
そうそう
She was fishing too.
みんなが 皆さんが 一緒に遊んでるのを やっぱ 自分だけやっぱね あの まあ参加しようと思ってもね
I didn't want to be left out when all of you were together, but I couldn't get a hold of the game right away,
いきなりあの 手に入れられるような 状態ではなかったんでね
even if I wanted to participate.
まあでも 手元にたまたまね あの まああの近いゲームがあったんで みんなと一緒に遊びたいと思って
But I happened to have a similar game in hand. So I figured I could join you all in spirit.
同じようなもの連れてたしね
You were fishing up the same things, too.
そう 結局ね あのほぼ同じような感じだったんだよ
Yeah. They were basically the same.
あのゴミも釣れますし なんか色んなものも釣れますし
I fished up trash, and a bunch of other things, too.
あの なので まあ 本気で あれね 優勝狙ってたんすよ でも
So, like... I was seriously trying to win.
まあね
Well, yeah.
こちらとしても ちゃんとね あの やってましたよ
We were tallying your points on our side, too.
あの点数計算 ちゃんと したんだけど 結果 まあ 優勝ではなかった
In the end, she didn't win. I think I got pretty close, though.
なるほどね
I see.
惜しかったね
You were pretty close.
懐かしいな
That takes me back.
懐かしい
Yeah.
あれめっちゃ楽しかった
It was really fun.
ありがとうございます 本当に いっぱい遊んでくれて
Thanks for playing with me at the time.
あとおかゆ先輩もね ご迷惑いろいろおかけしました
I've caused Okayu-senpai a lot of trouble, too.
いやいや全然だよ
Not at all!
なんかね あの おかず事件がね
The Okazu incident, for one...
出ました出ました おかずね
There it is, Okazu!
あれでも あれね
But like,
思い返すと 僕からね言い出したことだからね
looking back, I was the one who said that first.
あれなんか 私が無理やりおかゆ先輩のこと おかずって そんな言った感じに映ってますけど あれ実際先輩が
Did you guys notice how I was forced to call her \"Okazu\"? She actually called herself that first.
自分から自分から名乗っちゃってて だから私名乗っちゃってたの おかゆ先輩
She called herself that, huh? Yeah. That...
そう
She called herself that, nooka.
でもね 望みじゃん 望み おかずに なりたいっていう そういうことでしょう
She's wishing for it at that point. Wishing? To be fap material? Yeah. That's what it means, right? To be fap material?
バレちゃったか
I've been exposed.
バレちゃった
She's been exposed!
それ言っちゃっていいのか
Should you be saying that?
だめだめ
Nooo!
だめだめだめ
That's not allowed!
だめなのか
Is it? Is it not allowed?
だめですだめだよ やめてくださいよ
No! Please stop! That's not allowed!
私の卒業ライブですよ なんてこと言ってるんですか
What the hell are you saying on my graduation stream?!
いやでも やっぱここちゃんとのね 一番の思い出と言えばみたいなとこあるからね
But it is the most memorable thing I share with you, Coco-chan.
一番の思い出が おかず
The most memorable thing is... \"Okazu\"?
あぁ
Yeah. In that case...
まあまあしゃあないのかな
I guess we can allow it... That's steamy.
ここちゃんも 僕との思い出と言えば やっぱおかずになっちゃいますね
How about you? What was your most memorable thing with me? It would be \"fap material\", huh?
なっちゃいますね
What?
Seriously?
いや めちゃくちゃ楽しかった ですからね めちゃめちゃ楽しかった
You too?! It was really fun, after all. It was! It was!
旗から見ても おかずだもん
It's gotta be fap material for everyone else, too.
えっ
Hmm? What do you mean?
いや旗から見ても おかずが思い出みたいなとこあるじゃん
It's that moment for everyone else, too. That thing must've been memorable for everyone, right?
あぁ思い出が おかずってことね
Ah, so that's what you mean. That confused me.
違う意味に聞こえちゃいましたけど
That's what I mean. That confused me. I thought she meant something else.
Did I... say something weird?
そうですね うん
Yeah. I was wondering how to continue the conversation from that.
「おかゆは飯だな」とか 言った方がいいのかなとか
Like, \"Should I say, 'Okayu's some good ****in' food!' or something?\"
そっちの ちょっと違う意味に 聞こえちゃいますかね
That would mean something different entirely.
確かにね
Yeah. You would've just made things worse.
危ない危ない
Close shave.
なので あの たったの 1年と 7ヶ月くらい
Anyway, we've only spent a year and 7 months together,
でしたけれども 皆さんとね こうやって楽しく過ごせて私は本当に 感謝しかありません
but I'm thankful for all the fun moments we had.
先輩方 皆さん あの あの 今日 卒業しちゃって しまいますがい
I'll be graduating today, but I hope you all won't forget me!
どうにか 皆さん あの 桐生ココ あの 忘れないでいただきたいなって
Kiryu Coco! Please don't forget me! I want... Ah, thank you!
忘れるわけないやん 忘れるわけないじゃん
Of course we won't! We could never forget you, idiot!
ここちゃん 本当にありがとうございました
Coco-chan! Thank you for everything!
というわけで 本日来てくれました ホロライブゲーマーズの先輩方でした
Give it up for the members of hololive Gamers!
ありがとうございました
Thank you for coming!
ありがとうございました わあ
Thank you for having us! Whooo!
それでは、えー次は3期生の、えー先輩の皆さんとお話を最後にさせていただきたいと思います。
And next up, I'll be talking to all the members of the 3rd Gen one last time!
先輩！
Hello!
最後じゃないでしょ！
Don't call it the last!
困ってるよ！困ってるよ！
She's really flustered!
みんなで笑って笑って！笑おう！笑顔でお願いしますよ！
Let's all smile! Yes, please! Let's do this with a smile!
まああの短い期間でしたけれども、
Well, it was only for a short while,
えー、皆さんとはたくさんね、あの、絡むことができて、
but I got to interact with you all loads.
皆さんすごく優しくしていただいて本当にね、あの、本当にいい思い出しかないんですけども、
You've all been so nice to me, and I have so many good memories with all of you,
まあその中でもちょっと、あの、なんか印象といいますか、ありましたら聞きたいななんて思ってるんですけども。
but I was hoping that if you have any particularly good memories or impressions, you might share them with us today.
やっぱ会長がさ、デビューしたときさ、今ぺこらたちにとってはさ、初めての後輩ぺこちゃんだからさ、
So like, when you first debuted, you were our first juniors, right?
あ、そうそう！初めて！そうだよね！
Yeah, that's right!
え、やばくなかった？なんか最初のぺこらの初配信見たときに、あの印象がなんかもうすごすぎて、え、やばい奴来ちゃったってぺこら思った。
When I took a sneak peek at the first stream, I was just mindblown. I was like, "This girl's off her rocko!"
うんうんうん！そうそう！
Yeah, me too!
あれすごかったよね、本当にね、なんか...
It was pretty amazing... Like...
本当にすごかったし、あの初めてだよね、なんかね、男女初配信で泣いたの初めて。
It really was. And it was the first time I ever cried watching a debut stream, too.
泣いたの！？
You cried?!
え、だってみんな、YAGOOとの下り...
But the story with YAGOO was so touching!
いや、YAGOOとの下りめっちゃ感動したじゃん！ここで働きまーす！あれめっちゃ感動して、泣いちゃったんだよね！
It made me cry!
会長、感受性豊かか！
You're so emotional!
まあ私はやっぱ先輩なんですけど、一番なんというか、あの先輩の中で一番後輩なんで、一番ちょっと、なんていうか絡みやすいというか、っていう感じだったんですよ、あの、4期生からすると。
Well, you guys came before us, but you were the newest out of all the others. So all of you in the 4th Gen were the easiest to break the ice with, you know?
あー、確かに。
Oh, makes sense.
まあやっぱ船長的にはココさんのね、ご、ご実家に遊びに行ったっていうか泊まりに行って！
For me, it'd be when I went over... t-to her place. When you stayed over!
でね、まあそこでね、ココさんとね、もうびしょびしょにぬるぬるに濡れんだり（ベグンベグン）
And we got all dripping wet together.
ベグンベグン！ちょ、フレーズ！ヤバい！配信BANされちゃうでしょが！
Hey, phrasing! You want to get this stream banned?
え、でもしたよねココさん！びしょびしょにぬるぬる！
But we did, didn't we? Get all dripping wet?
それ真実なんでね、あの...
Yeah, it's true!
びしょびしょになりすぎて、ケツに痣ができました！
We went at it so hard, my arse got all bruised.
マリンにさ、ケツにできた痣の写真送ってくれましたよね！大切に保存してました！
Then you sent me a photo of it. I've kept it safe and secure.
大事にして下さい！
Yes. Please treasure it.
尻の... なにしてんだ！尻の割れ目...
Your... butt crack. What are they going on about?
写真、え、頂いて...
Thank you for the picture.
卒業してからも、大事にして下さい！
Please treasure it even after you graduate!
私の尻！
My arse!
尻の、私のね！パソコンのデスクトップにしときますね！
What?! Your butt crack... I'll set it as the wallpaper on my computer.
やめて！しないで！ありがとうございます！
Do not! Thank you so much!
ほかの皆は？あー、でも団長もあれだね、オフの話なんだけど。
What about everyone else? Actually, mine's about an offline occurrence too.
はいはい。
Oh?
そう、あの団長今ある、そのノエルスタジオが、あのカナココハウスの近くなんだよね。
So right now, my Noel Studio is pretty close to KanaCoco House.
そうそう！だからこそ、うん、あの、ココ会長にちょっとね、いいところを教えてもらって、
Yeah, it is. I managed to find a pretty nice place because Coco recommended it to me.
で、本当に2週間ぐらいなんか、何にも荷物が無い、空白時間があったんだよね。
So right at the start, I didn't have anything at all for about the first two weeks.
その時に、もう電気もなくて、え、どうしようってなったときに、
I was sweating because I didn't even have any lights!
そのカナココハウスからココ会長の、なんか昔使ってた電気を、あの、借りて、
But she brought me one of her old lights from KanaCoco House and was like,
えじゃあちょっと、あの引っ越した後に返すねって言って半月経つんだけど、まだリビングで使ってます！すみません！
"You can give it back after you're done moving," but it's been half a year and I'm still using it in my living room. I'm sorry!
借りパクだ！
You kept it! You totally just kept it!
全然大丈夫ですよ！
That's perfectly fine!
逆にちょっと卒業の記念にココさんだと思って持っていってもらって、
Now that she's graduating, maybe you can keep it as a memento of her.
ココさんだと思って使ってんだよ、団長のリビングで！大事にします！
Coco's shining in my living room! I'll take good care of her.
大事にします！
Yeah. Take good care of her!
すげえダサいライトなんですけどね、あの...
It's a really tacky light, though.
確かに、あの、なんか紐がついてるやつ、紐がついたらあのカチカチってやるやつ！
It's one of those lights with a string dangling down. One where you pull the string and it goes "click, click."
昭和み溢れる！ちょっと、あの、買った時のカナココハウスで使えなかったんで、
One of the old school ones. It was too tacky for KanaCoco House,
クローゼットにしまっといたんですけど、団長がね、緊急事態で部屋真っ暗だって言うんでね。
so I'd put it away in the closet, but she desperately needed a light...
じゃあこれからもね、大事にします！
I'll treasure it.
大事にして下さい！差し上げます！
Yes, please do! You can have it! It's all yours!
やい！差し上げる！やったー！
Yay!
あの、捨て方とか分かんなかったんでちょうどいい！ていうか、捨てないよもう！やめてー！
I didn't know how to get rid of it, anyway. There's no way she'll throw it out! Please stop...
でもオフでもね、皆さんお会いしましたから結構。
But really, we did all meet in person quite a lot.
私も、オフの思い出...
Mine's an offline thing, too.
お、るしあ！
Rushia!
あの、やばいね、やっぱ一番はなんかこう、引っ越しのきっかけ。
For me, it was how she spurred me on to move.
そうだよね、るしあちゃんずっと悩んでたもんね、るしあね。
That's right! You couldn't decide whether to move or not.
すごい積極的にね、物件をポンポンポンポン送ってくれて、
Well, she kept finding all these places and sending them to me,
それでなんか近くにこう、いるんだなって思って、安心するじゃん、で...
and it was also really reassuring knowing that she'd live nearby.
頼りになるし、すぐ引っ越して、で、すぐ引っ越したその日に...
Yeah, it is. I'd be able to get her help with things. So I ended up moving, and the day that I moved,
ココちゃんとかなたん...
I met up with Coco-chan and Kanatan...
ココちゃんと かなたんが
何笑ってんの？
What are you laughing about?
秘密！
It's a secret!
話の幅広さが 半端なかったっすね
You were so fast!
あったか？
That just makes me more curious...
そんで、それから
Then after that,
ココちゃんとかなたんが連絡くれるようになって
they would often contact me,
ココちゃんが こう、遊びにきてよみたいなね、カナココハウスによく呼んでくれて
and Coco-chan would often invite me to go hang out at KanaCoco House.
たくさんたこ焼きとかしたよね
We had lots of takoyaki parties, didn't we?
あ、よかったね！
That's so nice!
フレア先輩もね、あの、遊びに来ていただいて
You should come visit too, Flare-senpai.
行きたい行きたい！約束したもんね
I totally want to! We promised, right?
約束しましたもんね！行こうね
Yeah, we did!
お泊まりも来ていただきましたからね
You did stay the night once too!
いや、マジでさ、ココちゃんのさ、マットレスがさ、自分の自宅で使ってるやつよりもお客さん用の高かったのが結構印象的で
But like, what really left an impression on me was that the mattress I use for my own bed at home.
いや、ココさん優しいな！思いやりが
Coco-san's so kind! So thoughtful!
当たり前だろ！だってさ、
Well, there's no way that I can
そんな安っぽいあの、マットレスに寝かせるわけにはいかないじゃないですか！
let all of you sleep on a cheap mattress!
大先輩！
You're all my seniors!
優しいな
You're so thoughtful!
本当フカフカでした
It was so soft.
他のもね、ちょっとあの、用意させていただいて
Yeah. I put a really soft one in there.
本当にお世話になりました！私は
Thank you so much for everything!
もういなくなっちゃいますけど
I won't be here anymore...
本当楽しい思い出しかないので、笑顔でお別れができます
But I really did have a lot of good times, which is why I can leave with a smile today.
私たち4期生、あの、あと4人ね残りますから、あの、優しくしてやってくださいよ
The four other members of 4th Gen will still be here, though, so please continue to treat them well.
もちろんですよ！優しくしますよ
Yeah! Of course we will! We'll be kind.
本当に本日はありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for joining me today!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you for having us!
私、3期生の先輩方、みんな大好きです！
I love all of you 3rd Gens!
どういうことだよ！
What's up with that dance?!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
Thank you!
またねココちゃん！またねです！またね！
See you again, Coco-chan! See you!
それでは、えー、次は後輩のね、5期生が来てくれました！
Now then, next up are my juniors! The 5th Generation!
5期生の皆さん！
Hey, 5th Gen girls!
会長！
'Sup, Chairman!
すっ！すっ！
'Sup! Yay!
後輩ですね、これ
These are my juniors. So...
動きがすごい！
Your moves are amazing!
え？
Huh?
やっぱ先輩の動きはちげえわ
They're really on another level.
やっぱあの先輩ですからね、これぐらい動けるように先輩になるとなるんですよね
Because I'm your senior. You're able to move like this when you become someone's senior.
そう、先輩ですよ。知ってました？
So when you do... Yeah, I'm your senior. Didya know that?
知らない！
No!
すっ！すっ！
'Sup! 'Sup! I'm your senior!
先輩やめてください！
Please stop!
なんだこれ、もぐらたたきか！
What is this, whack-a-mole?
今日はね、まあ、あの5期生の皆さん、ちょっと、座り方がかっこ悪かったんですけど
Now I'll be talking with the 5th Generation. The way I just sat down was kind of lame.
あの5期生の皆さんと、一応ね、話す最後の機会ということで
Anyway, this is, well... It's officially our last chance to talk together.
さあ、そっか。皆さんとね、お話しできたらいいなって、思いまして、来ていただきました！
Ah, right. The last time. I thought it'd be nice if we could all have a chat, so here we are!
なんか思い出なんかもね、まあ、あんまり作る時間が一番やっぱ短かったんでね、皆さんと
You guys were, well, the ones I had the shortest amount of time to make memories with.
本当ですよ！
I know, right?!
あの皆さんとは数ヶ月ですかね。私はあのホロライブにいた時間自体が1年と7ヶ月ぐらいで
I only had a few months with you guys. My time in hololive was about a year and seven months.
で、皆さんがデビューしたのは、8月なので11ヶ月ですね。1年経ってない
And you guys debuted in... August. So about eleven months ago. Not even a year!
経ってないですよ！短いなー
That's right! That's not long.
まあでもね、その中でもなんかちょっと私の、まあ最後ですしね、ぶっちゃけちゃって印象なんかも言っちゃってもいいんじゃないですか？
Well, with that in mind, I thought... since this is the last time, maybe you could share your honest impressions of me and stuff!
えー！第一印象とか言います？第一印象！
Oh? How about our first impression, then? First impression!
聞きましょ、聞きましょ！それが一番大事、マスト
Okay, let's hear them. That's the most important. A must!
あのね、初配信の時の、最初の入りのアニメ、手書きアニメみたいなの
During your debut stream, you had that hand-drawn animation at the beginning.
あれがすごくて、それがすごい印象に残ってて
That was amazing! That really stuck with me. I thought it was great.
私も、自分がデビューする時もあんな最初からインパクトのある女になりたいなって
It made me want to become someone who could make an impact like that on her debut, too.
女に？
It did?
失敗した！
But I didn't. You didn't?!
失敗、失敗したのかな？
Did I mess up?
うん
Yeah.
え、本当ですか？
Huh? Really?
だんだん失敗してないと思いますけど
I think you succeeded.
やった！
Yay!
私ね、まあそうですね。皆さんにはそういうふうに印象に残って…
Well... this is my first time hearing how I've left a mark on you guys.
聞いたの本当初めてなんでちょっと嬉しい。
It's making me a little happy to hear.
じゃあラミちゃん、ラミちゃんラミちゃん最後ラミちゃん。
Okay, Lamy-chan! Lamy-chan, go next.
ラミは、もうここ先輩のことプレスリリースから見てるんで
Well, I first started watching you from your press release.
プレスリリースから！？
Since my press release?!
あなたの第一印象いつからですかそれ。
When exactly is your first impression, then?!
プレスリリースよ！
From then!
いやもうとにかくすごかった。タイフーンのような感じで、
Anyway, it was incredible! Your impact starting with your press release was like a typhoon!
もうプレスリリースからすごいインパクトがあったし、一人だけ身長もめちゃめちゃ高くて
Just for the fact that you were so tall!
あ、それは確かに。
That's true.
そうそう、すごかったし、
It was amazing.
初配信のインパクトもすごかったし、
And your debut stream was very impactful, too.
もうとにかくね、なんだろうホロライブに完全に新しい風が吹きまくってた。
Anyway, it was like you were a complete breath of fresh air for hololive.
ビュービューしてたね。
She blew right in.
お、褒めてるですね。褒めちぎってますね、これ。
Oh, she's really praising me. She's praising me so much, haha!
いやでも、ここ会長が入ってだいぶ変わってるそのなんか今までの流れがなんかもう本当に
But you really did shake things up when you joined.
で、この私たちもさ、やっぱりこの5期生としてデビューして分かるけど、あの新人としてデビューして
After we debuted as the 5th Generation, we can understand now how incredibly hard you had to work as a newcomer
やっぱ先輩たちに協力してもらって朝ココをやるとかさ、そういうのってどれだけ大変かってやっぱり入ってみて分かるじゃん。
to get your seniors to collaborate with you on Morning Coco and things like that.
労力のね、使い方とかね。もちろん。
And how you made sure to be low-risk when featuring them.
いや本当ね、あの初めてできた、なんていうかこう、まあ遠慮なしにいじっていい後輩なのでね、私にとっては。
Well, you guys were my first juniors, so how do I say... I could tease you without any hesitation.
そうなんですよ。私はね、あの、まあ先輩とか結構朝ココとかでいじったりしてきんですけど
I mean, I teased my seniors in Morning Coco, too.
あの先輩はちょっとね、あのすいません、先輩あの、あの顔面とか爆発したり頭飛ばしたりしていいですかねって
But I had to ask like, "Excuse me, can I use this image of you with your face exploding?"
結局結局そうすね、あのちょっと聞いたりしてたりしてたんですよね。
So you had to... Yeah, I had to ask them for permission and stuff.
あの、後輩に関しちゃねもうなんでもいいかなと思ってあんまりなんかくに本当にね、あの爆発とか
But for you guys, well, whatever! I could just blow you guys up without asking first.
そうだった。
I see.
私最初のコラボが会長だったんですけども、完全に爆発しましたね。7人ぐらい爆発しましたね。
My first collab was with you, and you really did blow me up. About seven times!
してましたね。
I did, didn't I?
で、最初はぎこちなかった、すごいお互いなんかあ、あ、あ、どこまでどこまで、あ、あ、みたいななっちゃった。やっぱり。
Back then, we were both really awkward, like... "Oh man, how far can I take it?"
でももう今こうやってね、あの普通に話してくれてるので、すごいあの、まあちょうど馴染みをしていた時だったんでね、突然卒業して。
But now, we can talk together normally like this. We all just got friendly with each other. So I'm sorry for graduating so suddenly!
すまんの！
Sorry!
会長！
Chairman!
許す！不帰！許す！
I forgive you! Unforgivable! I forgive you!
まあやっぱりでも、会長も朝ココやってた時って多分一番後輩としての立場でやってたじゃないですか。
When you were streaming Morning Coco, you were at the bottom of the totem pole, right?
もちろんね。それでもなんかそのホロメン同士をやっぱり繋ぐね、ハブとしての機能を果たしてたわけじゃないですか。
Absolutely. But even then, you really brought people together. You were like a hub for all the hololive members.
で、ま5期生もなんかここ会長みたいにね、うん、ならないとねっていうのはちょっとと思ってます。
It makes me think that we in the 5th Gen need to be a little more like you.
うん、マジで真面目。
A srs bzns answer. But I agree!
本当だそうた。そうだよ。
That's right.
助けて会長！今さら。会長どうしたらいい？俺たちどうしたらいいんだ会長。
Help us, Chairman! While the clock's running out! Chairman, what should we do?
アドバイスを！アドバイスを！アイスクリーム！
Do you have any advice? We need advice!
あのあの、遠慮せずにね、あの先輩とか普通にあの皆さん優しいんで知ってると思いますけど、皆さん本当ね、あの話やすく優しい方々なので
I think you already know, but all the hololive members are really nice and approachable.
まあ、私の時はね、ちょっとあの、まあ特別というか、まあある意味好きに暴れられたのでね、皆さんの時とはちょっと違うかもしれないんで、
Well, it was a bit different for me at that time. I was able to run wild a bit. That might be a little different for you guys now.
あの、皆さんね、皆さんのやり方でぜひあの視聴者の方をね、楽しませてほしいと私は思うんですよ。
I want you guys to entertain your viewers in your own special way.
先輩からの最後のアドバイスとはそれかな。
I suppose that is my final advice to you.
そのギガギガを攻めていきます。
We'll continue pushing that envelope!
重いよ！
The gravity...!
楽しく、楽しくね、あのやればいいんじゃないかな。私もね楽しかったからやってただけなんなんで。で、思いますよ。
If you just have fun with it, it's all good, right? That's all I really did. Just had fun with it! That's what I think.
まあでも君たちこれから君たちもね、あの先輩になる時が来る。
You'll eventually see new members pop up, too.
そういう時にね、あの後輩をね、あのどう教育するかは君たちにかかっている。そういうわけ。
And how you lead them, well... that's up to you. That's how it is.
なのでね、あのブザマみせんじゃないぞ。
Don't embarrass yourself, okay?
はい！
Yay!
わかりました会長！
Understood!
旨味分かりました！見ててください！
Got it! Please watch us!
見ててください、俺ら頑張りますんで！
Please watch us work hard!
声が汚い、声が。
God damn, no need to bellow!
それでは、皆さん、5期生の皆さんでした！今日は来てくれて、あ、ありがとね！
Give it up for the 5th Gen! Thank you so much for coming!
やった！ありがとうございます！愛してる！
Yay! Thank you! Thank you so much! I love you!
はい、ではここからはホロライブENの後輩ともに聞いてもらいましたよ！
Okay! Now I've got the members of hololive English here!
皆さん、Thank you for coming to my Kiryu Group Headquarters!
Guys! Thank you for coming to my Kiryu Group Headquarters!
ホロライブENの皆さんイエーイ！
hololiveEN peeps! Yay!
皆さん、Thank you for coming to my graduation stream!
Guys! Thank you for coming to my graduation stream!
Oh, don't feel sad!
Of course! Of course!
Any time for you, Senpai.
ありがとう、来てくれて。
Thanks for being here!
今日はね、あの私の、まあ卒業ということで、色々ね、あのまあ後輩なんでね、ちょっと私と一緒に過ごす時間は皆さんよりかは少なくなってしまいましたが、
Today, well, it's my graduation. And my juniors here, well, haven't had as much time with me as everyone else,
いろんなね、印象とかあったら聞いていこうかと思ったし、
but I'd like to hear what your memories of me are like.
So guys! Well, you guys... As you guys know, I am graduating, but umm...
What did you guys uh... think about uh... Kiryu Coco?
What did you guys think about Kiryu Coco?
You have any memories?
Iconic!
Iconic?
An absolute icon.
Really? Was I?
And literally the reason we are here.
We wouldn't be here without you, Senpai. We freakin' love you!
Oh god, really?
How about you, Kiara-chan?
Uh, in the beginning, I thought that... When I saw your debut stream... I thought that you were a really creative and funny dragon.
But also an insanely hard worker from the beginning, because you did stuff like Morning Coco. And I thought that was like... anything you did was really interesting.
But one thing that I was worried about is... if it's not difficult to speak when your tongue is always sticking out!
True!
At that time my mouth was like always open, I know! I remember.
Yeah! And my tongue was always sticking out, and I was... It looked like I was speaking with my tongue out always. It was like...
Plus, I kinda sounded like I was like... you know, I had the... Well, I do right now, but a nasal voice. It kinda really looked like I was really talking with my tongue out.
But I wasn't! I wasn't! It just looked like that.
How about you, Ina-chan?
Ina-chan! Thank you for coming!
Thank you for having us!
I know we didn't have much time to interact with each other, but, you know... We're BFFs, right?
Yeah.
Well... How could I forget your legendary 3D debut stream? Your dance moves just... wow. Captivating. Legendary.
Aw, thank you! Thank you so much!
みんな意外と私の配信見てくれてて、嬉しいな。
They all watch my streams more than I thought. That makes me happy!
Amelia! Thank you for coming!
Thank you for having me!
Now that Ina mentioned your birthday stream, I remember we were all watching... uh, your 3D debuts, I think together in Discord around that time.
And I remember when you flipped! You did a flip and we were like, 'Did she just do a flip?! What the hell?!'
It was insane!
You guys wanna see it again?
Really?!
Yes!
Can I do it? Can I? Oh yeah, let's go!
Whoa! That's so awesome!
I can do it any time.
I can't do that. I can't even do a handstand. Damn!
What?!
みんな意外と私の配信見てくれててさ、そしてさらにね、私のこうやってね、あのいろんなね、記念配信とかも実はね裏でDiscordとかで一緒に見てくれてたんですね。
They've all been watching my streams! And they were watching my celebration streams all together in Discord.
Well, I wish I had more time to, you know... do collabs and do funny stuff with you guys.
And I really regret that I couldn't interact with you guys in 3D.
Yeah... That would have been so fun.
I wanted to dance with you guys! I wanted to dance with you guys!
Calli-chan, we played games together.
We kinda interacted... well, how many times was that, like... Gosh, like three? Three collab streams?
Gosh, like three? Three collab streams? Yeah!
Sometimes playing on the side. Yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
I remember I thought your cover of "Shitsureishimasu ga, RIP" was so amazing,
and I got so excited every time I saw it!
I have one regret.
I just couldn't complete that fast from that... "Shitsureishimasu ga, RIP"...
It is so fast. I can't pronounce it right.
I mean, that's okay. Even I can't. It's written to be that way,
but you know what? I thought your spirit was so fantastic.
I couldn't help but have a big smile on my face watching you sing that.
Thank you!
You've got the makings of a great rapper, Senpai.
Can I continue practicing that "Shitsureishimasu ga, Rest in Peace"...
Uh, that "RIP" after my graduation?
Absolutely! Of course you can, Senpai. Any time that you want.
It's so amazing.
Thank you so much! I wanna say, like, you...
You were really a big inspiration to me.
When I was gonna join—when I was thinking about auditioning for hololive, I was really nervous at first, kinda wondering,
"Oh, am I gonna be able to kinda like..." I mean, I kinda have a bit of a big personality.
But you just kind of, you do what you want. And it really kinda made me feel like, "Oh, wow! I wanna try and do that, then."
So I just wanna say thank you from the bottom of my heart.
Please! Please, you guys! I appreciate you, Senpai.
It's a message from me to you guys. To the "kouhais" of EN:
Please, please don't stop being yourself.
Please don't stop trying and trying to do new stuff. Challenging! Please, do not stop doing that.
And don't forget about me ever! Okay?
Never, Senpai! We'll never forget you, ever!
How could we forget you?
Oh no! Someone just disappeared again!
Overwhelmed by emotions! The chicken flies the coop again!
Kiara-chan disappears once in a while to control her emotions.
Our time together was a bit short, but I'm glad I got to become friends with the EN members.
I'll forever think of them as my friends.
Now then, EN peeps...
Thank you! Thank you for coming!
Thank you for being here!
Bye-bye, guys! Thank you, Senpai! Goodbye!
We love you, Coco! Don't you forget about me! Don't you ever! Don't you ever!
I'll miss you! Kiryu Group forever!
Bye-bye! Goodbye, Senpai!
And coming up next, we've got EN's Gawr Gura-chan! Thank you for coming, Gura-chan!
Gura-chan! Gura-chan! Gura-chan!
Hey, Gura-chan!
Coco-senpai! Hiii!
Thanks for coming.
Thank you for having me! You're all by yourself!
Yeah!
Well, uhm... So, this is my graduation stream today. And I wanna know what...
Well, we had some memories together, didn't we?
Yeah, yeah!
Well, I hoped we had more, but yeah, we had memories... Like, uh...
Usada Construction Summer Festival!
Yeah, you couldn't find me! I was lost.
It was fun playing with you, so... Yes.
Gura-chan, what do you think about idol Kiryu Coco?
I think Kiryu Coco is amazing! Kiryu Coco idol is amazing!
Yes, I have a obsessive yet healthy curiosity and obsession with... Wait, obsessive...
Kiryu Coco-senpai idol. Yes!
Yes, I am an idol! And I think you are an idol too!
Well... If you say so...
Gura-chan, well, I really wanted to play with you more.
It was... It was a... It was a short time. I wanted to collab with you more. I wanted to play games with you more.
And I regret that I didn't have time to do that.
Gura-chan, how 'bout you?
I wish we... I wish we could have played, like, ARK together.
Oh, ARK? Yeah!
Do you like ARK?
I've never tried it, but I wanted to try it with you! Yeah! You should and...
Gura-chan, promise me right now you will play ARK with the hololive members. Promise me!
We're playing ARK, everybody! Let's go!
So thank you, Gura-chan, for coming!
Thank you, thank you!
では、次は何とこちらの事務所に初めて、インドネシア組のみんなが来てくれました！
Now up are first-time visitors to the HQ, the Indonesian members!
こんにちは、ホロライブIDの皆さんです！
Hello, everyone from hololive ID!
イェーイ！
Yay!
もうね、もう全員勢揃いですよ。こんなことありますか皆さん！
Wow, it's the whole lineup! Can you believe it?
今日はね、私の卒業ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you all for coming to my graduation stream today.
悲しく、悲しくならないでくださいね。
Please don't be sad!
まあね、あのID組の皆さんとはね、ちょっとまあ絡む機会は少し、まあ少なかったかもしれないですけど、
I didn't have much of a chance to interact with the ID members,
でもね、一緒に遊んでくれたり、まあちょっと残念ながら遊べなかった子たちもいたんですけども、
I did get to hang out with some of you... but unfortunately not all of you.
皆さん、私の第一印象ってありますか？
So, what were your first impressions of me?
What do you think about Kiryu Coco?
What did you think about Kiryu Coco?
第一印象ですか？
Our first impressions?
そうそうそうそう！
Yeah!
誰からいきます？
Who wants to go first?
あ、じゃあ、りすちゃん！
Then how about Risu-chan?
私からね。
Starting with me, okay.
I think of Kiryu Coco as Superdragon!
Superdragon, yay!
Always brave and cheerful, yes.
I always look up to Coco-senpai!
ココ先輩！
Coco-senpai!
Thank you.
ココ会長だ！会長！
Chairman Coco!
ありがとうございます、りすちゃん！
Thank you, Risu-chan!
りすちゃんは、あの、ちょっと二人でいろいろ配信したりっていう機会がなかなかなかったので、もっと仲良くなりたかったですけれどもね、ね、りすちゃん！
Risu-chan and I didn't really get a chance to stream together. But I wanted to get friendlier with her. Right, Risu-chan?
うん、うん、うん！
Mhm!
じゃあ、ムーナは？
How about Moona?
First impression of Coco-senpai, uh... is cool! So cool!
Really? More than you?
Yeah, yeah!
Yeah!
I think Moona's cooler. And so nice! I love you. I love you.
ムーナはね、あのID組で唯一二人でね、Reddit Shitpost Review一緒にね、できたんでね、まあ本当に、実は本当はみんなとやりたかったんですけどね、
Moona was the only one from the ID group I got to do a Reddit Shitpost Review with! I really wanted to be able to do it with all of them, though!
時間が取れなくてごめんね。でもたくさん、たくさん遊んでくれましたからね。
Sorry for running out of time. But we had a lot of fun.
イオフィちゃん！
lofi-chan!
はい！もっと遊びたかったですよね。
Yes! I wanted to hang out with you more.
ね、もっといっぱいお話とか絵描きとかしたいね。
Me too! I want to talk with you and draw with you!
で、えっと、卒業してからもね、うん。
Yeah! Maybe after I graduate.
どうなんだろうね、第一印象って言えば一言で言えば……
Well, my first impression, if I had to put it simply...
やばいかな？
"What the hell!" I guess?
やばいってなんだよ！
What's that supposed to mean?!
えっと、あれあれあれ、えっと、やばい、この人面白いとか、え、やばい、美人とか、そういうのやばいですよ。
I-I mean... Like "What the hell! She's so funny!" or "What the hell! She's beautiful!" That's what I mean.
そんなやばい、そんなやばい、マジマジマジ。
So in a good way.
そう、いい方の、セクシーな方の。
In a sexy way. Right? A good "what the hell!"
そうそうそうそう、この人やばいセクシーだ、やばい面白いとか、
"What the hell! She's sexy!" "What the hell! She's funny!"
やべえ、セクシー？
Yeah! Sexy?
そうそうそうそう。
Really?
でも、褒められちゃってるから嬉しい！イオフイちゃんともっと一緒に遊びたかったな。
Well, you're praising me, so I'm glad to hear it. I wish we could have hung out more, Iofi-chan.
遊びたかった！オリー！
Me too! Ollie!
オリー、この野郎！
Ollie, you SOB...
この野郎って！
SOB...?!
when when I first saw, um, Coco-senpai, I had the same thought as iofi-senpai. I thought you were a sexy mama!
When I first saw Coco-senpai, I had the same thought as iofi-senpai. I thought you were a sexy mama!
ありがとうございます、オリーちゃん！卒業してからも仲良くしてくださいね。
Thank you very much, Ollie-chan! Let's stay close after I graduate!
うんうんうんうん！
Yeah, yeah!
そして、アニャ！
And now Anya!
はい！えっと、第一、第一印象ですね。あのデビューの前からでも、あの結構私朝ココ見てて、
Yes! My first impression, huh. Before I debuted, I used to watch Morning Coco quite a bit.
あ、ずーっと見てて、いや、ずーっと見てる朝ココ、え、since the OG days, I think.
Oh! An addict! Yeah, I've been watching Morning Coco since the OG days, I think!
そう、そう、そう、そう。そう、My first impression of you was from that. And I thought you were quite insane.
So my first impression of you was from that. And I thought you were quite insane.
Oh god, she-crazy?!
Crazy! Insane! But, you know, in in good meaning, in good ways.
Crazy! Insane! But, you know, in good meaning, in good ways.
あ、ありがとうございます、アニャ。良い意味で。
Aw, thank you so much, Anya. In a good way!
Your presence in general. 雰囲気とかからも、
Your presence in general.
存在感からもう
My presence?!
滲み出てたし
Did I ooze it?!
好き！いやいやいやいや
You like it!
優しですしもう、あのCoco先輩は
And you're kind.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
もっと遊びたかったですね
I wanted to hang out with you more.
そう、あなたね、もう本当、一番ね、遊べる機会が取れなかったんじゃないかと思ってすごくね、あの
I think you were the one I had the least chance to spend time with.
そうですよね！ウチは残りがありますね、あや！
Yeah. That's a big regret of mine, Anya!
ありますね！
Me too.
あの、卒業してからこっそりじゃあたくさん遊びましょうね！
Let's have a ton of fun in secret after I graduate, then!
遊びましょう！
Let's do that!
やった！遊びましょう！Thank you!
Thank you!
そして、Turkey！
And now... hey! Turkey!
What?!
You...
You [redacted]!
Coco-senpai, my first impression of you is that you are so smart in marketing your products. You're very good at it. Very nice.
Your commercials, too! They're very, very good.
And as I thought, you have a very, very nice... Very nice moves! And a very... big... big... Big personality, yeah!
Thank you! Thank you so much! Thank you so much for teaching me Indonesian, and teaching me your culture, and teaching me how to... how to cook turkey, and teaching me how to say jan***!
Thank you! Thank you so much! Thank you so much for teaching me Indonesian, and teaching me your culture, and teaching me how to cook turkey, and teaching me how to say jan***!
Thank you!
It's okay. You're a very good gaku... gakusei... student. Yes. Gakustudent!
I feel like the two of us made a lot of memories in that last stream where you taught me Indonesian.
Indonesian members! Thank you for all the fun memories and for becoming friends with me! Thank you so much!
Thank you, ID! hololive Indonesia, everybody!
Thank you! Thank you, everybody! Minna arigatou gozaimashita! Bye-bye!
Thank you! Thank you, everybody! Bye-bye!
それでは次は、4期生ですね。最後にきてもらいました！全事務所に呼び出しだ！
And finally, we have my 4th Gen mates to cap it all off! They're all here at HQ!
4期生の！おい、これ！
Here they ar-Yo, hey! Yaaay!
うおおお！うれしい！
Woohoo! We're here!
呼び出された！面接か！これもう！
Is this an interview?
わあ！何これ、なんだこの空気は！
Yay! What's this place...? What's with this mood?!
ちょっといい席用意したから。ほら。
I have good seats for you guys.
いい席？初めて来たここ。
It's our first time here. Good seats? First time?
初めて！初めて！ようこそようこそ。これ桐生会事務所よ、どう？
Welcome! Make yourselves at home. Whaddya think of the HQ?
これ、ちょっとリクライニングには合わないんじゃねえの、この椅子。
I don't think this chair's for me...
いや、お気に召さないようだぞ。
It seems she doesn't like it.
結構文句出てますけど。うるせえな！
We already have complaints! Oh, shut it, will ya?
うるせえな。パルプースの順序おまえら！
Shut yer traps. Shooed off!
これ、またはスチールチェアー？
This, or steel chairs?
やめろ！
Cut it out!
ありがたくしろ！
Be thankful, then!
今日はね、まあ、こうして
Yeah. Today will be the, uh,
まあ、ね。普通に話すのは最後になるわけだ。卒業、卒業ライブだよ今日は。卒業ライブの配信というわけでね。
this'll be the last time we can talk like this, since today's my graduation event and all.
はい。
Yeah.
最後にやっぱり4期生のね、同期のみんなと話しておきただなと思いまして。
So I thought, why not have a talk with all of 4th Gen?
今まで先輩とか話聞きましけど、まあね。
I've talked to the others too, but yeah...
まあ、呼び出そうおまえらは。
I've summoned y'all here now.
呼び出された。
We've been summoned...
特別だからな！
You're special to me!
何されるんですか。やだ、怖い。
What are you gonna do to us? I'm scared! I'm going home!
なんかされるんかい？
You expecting something?
何？それ殿のな？
What...? Your grin gives it away.
にやにやしやがって。喜んでるぞ、これ。
She's enjoying this! I wonder what she'll do... Hehehe.
まあ、ちょっとした思い出とか、中、そういうの語る。どんな、なんでもいいけど！
I'm feeling like looking back, talking about some memories... Well, it could be anything, really! Could be anything.
うん、まあ、いろいろね、ちょっと話したこといっぱいあるよね、あー。
There's a lot we could talk about, yeah.
ない！
None!
え、嘘でしょ、ちょっと！待って待って！カットカットで、もう今の！
You serious?! That's a wrap! You sure about that? Cut that part out! That didn't count!
まあ、まあ、まあ、やだ、から、まあね。そうね、改めてってね、言うとね。
Well, well... I mean... Yeah... Now that you mention it... That's right.
なんか緊張、緊張なった思うけど。
I got pretty nervous there.
みんなでね、
Yeah... Everyone here...
え、これ手紙？
A letter?
あっそう、今日はね、4期生
Yeah, everyone in 4th Gen...
みんなだって、手紙を書いてきまして、あ、ここよ送る言葉をね。
Yeah, everyone in 4th Gen wrote letters containing our messages for you, Coco.
なんか持ってんね。
Oh, ya holding something.
そうなんだよ、実はね。
Right.
持ってないけども。
I'm not holding it yet, though.
持って…？
Holding...?
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
うお！ 手紙を…
Whoa! It's a letter!
手紙を書いてまいりまして。
We all wrote our own letters!
あ、それを読みつつ、思い出話をしつつな感じでね、いきたいと。
And we'll be reading them while looking back at everything that we've done together.
思いまーす。
Yep.
え、誰から読むの？
Who do we start from?
誰から読むの？ これ？
Who wants to start? Who's taking dibs?
決めてないね？
We didn't decide, right?
全然、順番決めてなかったね。
Yeah, we haven't. Fine.
じゃあ、わため、わためから、こっちから…。
All right, let's start with Watame.
お、いいの？
I go first?
大丈夫？ トリ飾れますかね？私。
Uh, you sure you want me last?
お前、トリかよ！
Oh wait, you're going last!
喜べよ！
Be glad!
じゃあ、わため、わためから…。
Watame, if you please.
一番、トップバッター。
Lead-off hitter!
ふう…。では…
Okay, then.
お手紙。
Here's my letter.
お手紙、読みたいと思います。
I will be reading it now.
かわいいのに書いてきてる。
There's a cute drawing in it, too.
お、そうだ！
Oh, yeah!
女子戦、見せて？
Show it to us!
ありがとうよ。
Thanks.
ふわふわなやつに書いてきて。
I drew it real fluffy.
めくる…めくれないよ。
I can't open it...
なんかちょっとドキドキしてきた。
I'm getting all nervous now!
なんで？
Don't be!
緊張するんだけど。
I'm super nervous!
緊張したままでいいよ。
Relaxation is fine, though.
では読みます。
I'll start.
はい。
Sure.
ここちへ。
To Cocochi,
まさかこんな手紙を書く日が来るとはな。
I never thought I'd need to write a letter like this!
誕生日のときにビデオレターも渡したけど、
I did give you a video message on your birthday,
改めてお手紙を書くね。
but for today, it'll be on paper.
私はデビューが決まった時、
When my debut was decided,
嬉しさ半分、不安半分で、4期生のみんなに馴染めるかなとか、
I was somewhat happy, and somewhat worried if I could fit in with everyone in 4th Gen,
ほとんど緊張…、あ、噛んじゃった。
or if a nobod—ah, I flubbed. Got tongue-tied, huh!
経験がない自分でも活動できるかなとか、そんな気持ちでいっぱいでした。
or if a newbie like me would do well at all. That's what I felt.
サムネの作り方も、それを造るために必要なことも知らなくて、
I didn't even know how to make thumbnails for my videos or what I needed to make them.
デビューしてからも緊張しいで、クソ雑魚回線な私は、
And even after debut, I kept freaking out, and had a crappy connection.
そうだったな。
Those were the times!
懐かしいなあ。
How nostalgic...
あんまりポジティブではなかったと、思われます。
I didn't have much of a positive outlook back then.
そうなの？
Really?
うん。なんかちょっと遅れをとったような。
I felt like I was lagging behind.
本当？ そんな気持ちになった時はありました。
That's what I felt like early on.
でもそれらすべてを打ち砕いてくれたのが、ここちの存在だったのです。
The person who managed to break me in despite everything is you, Cocochi.
ここがいたから、今私はくじけずにここに、まあ座ってるけど、立っていられます。
Thanks to you, Coco, I can stand here—well, I'm sitting, but—I can stand here without faltering.
そう言っても、過言ではありません！
I can say this with full confidence!
何げに朝こことかでも頼ってくれるのが嬉しかったし、
I'm really happy you let me be on Morning Coco,
相棒って呼んでくれるの、幸せだったよ。
and I'm happy to have been your partner.
ま、これからも私のたった1人の相棒なんですけどね。
You'll be my one-and-only partner, though.
もちろんさ！
Of course!
な！
Yeah!
だから卒業してもいつでも頼ってくれていいし、何でも力になるから遠慮せず声かけてくれよな。
Even once you graduate, you can always call on me whenever you feel like you need help!
ありがとう。
Thank you!
あ、それと！
Oh, and also!
私が武道館に立つときには、
When I take the Budokan stage,
ドラゴン用の特別席を用意するので、チケット、チケットを受け取ってくれよな！
I'll be preparing a dragon seat for you, complete with a VIP ticket!
おっと？
Really?!
最前列で腕組んだいいかい？
Can I be all proud in the front row?
うん。
Sure.
でかいかな？なでも。大丈夫かな？
You'd be pretty large, though?
「私が育てた」ってやっていいか。
"I raised that girl."
強えドラゴン。
Stwong dragon.
わためより！ わためありがとう！
Hooray! Love, Watame! Thank you so much, Watame!
まあ、お疲れですけど、まあ、わためのね、武道館が
This may be goodbye,
まだね、見れてないんで、それまではちょっとね、
but I've yet to see you perform at Budokan,
地球にようかな？
so I'll stick around on Earth until then.
おお、いてくれるの？
You'll stick around?
Hey, Watame!
わため頑張れ！
Go for it!
頑張りまーす！
I'll do my best!
ありがとうよ、わため。
Thanks, Watame.
こちらこそ。
No, thank you.
わためは、まあ、あそこでもね、常に
Watame was, well... She always replied instantly
まあ、レスが早かったんで、あのいっぱい使わしていただいた。
to my requests for help on Morning Coco.
なんかみたいな言い方だな！
Don't make her sound like she was easy!
My sheepy calls.
めっちゃ言われてた、便利羊だったからな。
You really were a convenient sheep.
まあでも、本当そのおかげでね、いろんなコンテンツが作れたんで、助かってたよ。
But it's thanks to you that we made a lot of things happen. Same here.
こちらこそ。
Thank you to you too.
あの、これからもね、楽しく、わためえ、わためえ、
That's why, moving forward... Watame-Watame—
わためのことは好きだから卒業してからも仲良く。
I love ya, Watame, so I hope to be friends even after grad.
まあ、なんかあったら、ほら、まあ、ま、卒業した者にしかわからない痛みみたいなあるじゃん。
If ya need anything, There's some things, some experiences only alumni would know.
なるほど！
I see!
そういうのいつでも受け付けたから。
AMA. Sure thing!
わかった！ 連絡するわすぐ。
I'll call you immediately!
うん、すぐ連絡しろよ！
Yeah, you better!
その、クソザコ執事じゃ、変わらねえよな？
I will! You'll still be the lightning-fast sheep, right?
そうや、すぐ連絡する、すぐ連絡してくれよな！
Yay! Yep! I'll call immediately!
ありがとうよ。
Thank you!
こちらこそ！
The pleasure's mine!
ルナもなんか書いてきてくれたんかい？
What did you write on yours, Luna?
いやあ、どうしようみんな！
Gosh, I feel so unprepared!
なにが？
What's the matter, Luna?
持ってるじゃん！
But you're holding something!
だって、だって…
'Cause I mean, I mean...
ルンな、ルンな… みんなお手紙書いてきたって言ってるけど、ルンのお手紙じゃないの！
'Cause I mean, I mean... Eveyone wrote letters, but I didn't!
なに？
Say what?!
何手持ってんだ
Then what's that?
これね、ルンので、絵を描いたの！
Well, I drew a picture for you!
おおっ！
Ooh!
見たい、見たい！これをね、ここちゃんにね、見せたいの！
I'm gonna show it to you, Cococha.
はい！おおっ！
Here you go! Ooh!
かわいい！
It's too darn cute!
かわいすぎだよ！
So cute!
母の日授業参観みたいだな、母の日授業参観みたいな
She's like a kid showing her mom a school project!
かわいすぎだろ
This is too cute!
どうやって説明すればいいの？
How do I expwain this?
大好き、ここちゃって書いてある！
It says, "Wuv you, Cococha!"
大好き、ここちゃん！
That's so sweet!
ここちゃんに、ここに「だいすき、ここちゃん」って書いたの。
I wrote, "Wuv you, Cococha" on it.
あとで額に入れて飾ろう。
I gotta frame this and hang it up.
あそこYAGOOの隣あたりに？
You can put it next to YAGOO.
え？
Over there?
飾るの？
You'll even hang it up?
もちろん！飾るならあのYAGOO、YAGOOいらねえから、YAGOOは
Of course! We can get rid of that YAGOO and put this there.
本当に？
Really?
あそこ飾ってくれるじゃんの。
I get to take his pwace?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ちょっと、あとで拡大印刷するしか
I've gotta take care of this later.
拡大印刷？
Gotta enlarge this at a print shop.
え、これ説明したいのよ！
Enlarge? I wanted to expwain my picture.
説明してほしいのよ！
Please do!
立って説明でいいの？
Can I keep standing?
あ、いいよ、いいよ。
Go ahead!
えっとね、これも「だいすき、ここちゃん」てことでね、ここちゃんの絵と、
It says, "Wuv you, Cococha" here with a picture of you.
あと4期生のね、顔…顔じゃなくて
And the other Gen 4 members' faces... Wait, not faces.
顔、顔？顔じゃなくて4期生のね、この、あのチャームポイント的なものをね、おひとりずつで書きました。
Not their faces, but like, symbols that represent each of them. I wrote it all by myself!
かわいいのら！
It's so cute!
ありがとう、ルナ！
Thank you so much, Luna!
ここちゃんに差し上げます。
This is for you, Cococha.
ありがとう！
Thank you so much!
受け取ってくださいまし！
Please take it.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
よかったー！
So sweet!
じゃあルナはほら、ココとの思い出でなんか、ある？
So, got any special memories with Coco?
ここちゃんとの思い出でね、一番はね、
Well, what I remember most...
あれなのよ、ホラーゲーム…
...is the time we played a horror game together.
あー、やった！
I remember that!
一番最初にね、ここちゃんとやったの。
It was the first thing we did together.
やってたね！
It sure was!
そう、座ろう、座ろう。
I'm gonna sit down.
またね、あの、一緒にいつでも遊べると思ってたからね。
I thought we'd always have more chances to play together.
うん、なんかね、そう、ここちゃんと何かやりたいと思ったの。ここちゃんって一番最初ね、ホラーゲームばっかりやってたんだよね。
'Cause like, I wanted to do something with you. And early on, you mostly played horror games.
あ、確かに！
That's right, I did!
ホラーゲームのイメージしかなかったんだよ。だから、ここちゃんとやる時はホラーゲームかなと思って、
I thought horror games were your thing, so if we played together, that's what we should do.
うん、頑張ってくれたのか、それですごい頑張ったけど、やっぱ怖すぎたからもうやめちまった！
Yeah, I tried my best, but they were too scary, so I quit.
やめちゃったの？！
You quit?!
やめちゃったけど、うん、それでもね、ここちゃんとできたすごい良い思い出だったの、怖いホラーゲームだけど！
I quit doing horror, but getting to play with you was a really nice memory.
私もすごい嬉しい！怖いゲームだったけど！
I'm so happy to hear that! The games were scary, though!
また一緒にて言えないのが悲しいけど、でも
I wish I could say, "Let's play again sometime."
ルナとは、もうちょっとやっぱ遊びたかったよな、ふたりきりで。
Even so... I wish we could have hung out more, just the two of us.
あーだめだよ！
Nooo! This sucks!
でもさ、卒業しても遊べるじゃん！
We can still hang out, even after you graduate!
絶対！
Absolutely!
みんなも？
With you guys, too?
みんなも！
All of us!
みんなで遊ぶの！
We can all have fun together!
遊ぼうや！
We can hang out!
遊びに来てください、カナココハウスに！
Drop by KanaCoco House anytime!
カナココハウスにいつでも来てよ！
To KanaCoco House! Our door's always open!
行く行く行く！
Sure! Of course!
たこパしてくれて！たこパする？
Can we have a takoyaki party?
やろうやろう！
Yeah, let's do it!
任せろ、任せろ、ここは。
Leave it to me. I'll do this part.
本当に？
She's good at it.
じゃあルナ、タコさん切るから！
She is?
おっ！切るの？
Then I'll chop up the octopus!
ルナが動き出す！
Really?
マジで？
Luna's taking charge!
ルナ、自分でやるか？
Luna, you're actually gonna do something yourself?
やるね！
I'll do it!
頼むぞ！
We're counting on you!
楽しみ！
Can't wait!
ではでは、次は、とわ、うま、なんか書いてきてくれたんかい？
Now, next is Towa! Did you write something for me, too?
そう、もうね。
Well yeah...
書きました。
I did!
ありがとうね。
Thank you... Thank you.
いや、なんか、とわね、うまくね、言葉にするのが苦手。やっぱり語彙力が
You know, I'm really not good at putting stuff into words.
薄い悪魔なんでね。
I'm a devil with a weak vocabulary. I wrote what I could.
素晴らしいレターをいただいて
Don't worry. It's not as weak as mine.
そんなことないの？
What?!
大丈夫？え？！
It's quite really bad.
いや結構、相当ひどいよ。
Quite really!
結構相当ひどいよ。
Quite really bad.
じゃあ、読ませていただきます。
Okay, I'm going to read it now.
うん、はい。
Go ahead.
と、ココへ。手紙を書くのは久しぶりです。ま、しかもね、本人を目の前で読む、読むのも初めてです。
Dear Coco, It's been a while since I've written a letter. And what's more, it's the first time I've ever read one to the person it's addressed to.
ま、少し恥ずかしいけど読みます。
It's a bit embarrassing, but here I go.
まずココのことを、ま、第一に、尊敬しています。
To start with, I look up to you, Coco. Your relentless positivity,
ま、いつもポジティブなところとか、優しいところ、言葉のチョイスが面白いところと、ま、いっぱいありますと。
your kindness, your amusing word choice, and much more.
デビューして、ホロライブを盛り上げたいと言っていて、それを実現させる力が本当にすごいなと思ってました。
When you debuted, you said you wanted more excitement in hololive, and I thought your ability to actually make that happen was amazing.
4期生それぞれデビューしてからの、いろいろ悩んでいたところを、ココがエンターテインメントとしてキャラクターを作ってくれたね、すごく助けられました。
After the rest of the 4th Gen debuted, we encountered various problems, and you turned them into entertainment and made them part of our identities. That was a big help to us.
ダンス練習も楽しかった。ご飯も行ったり、たこパしたり、思い出がたくさんあります。
Dance practice was fun, too. I have a lot of memories of us going out to eat, having takoyaki parties, and stuff like that.
ココの伝説はココが卒業してもずっと残っているし
Even after you graduate, your legend will continue to live on,
みんなの記憶に残っていることだと思います。
and I believe that nobody will forget you.
ココの卒業の話を聞いた時、驚きすぎて言葉が出てきませんでした。
When I heard that you were graduating, I was shocked speechless.
考えれば考えるほどやっぱり泣けたし、想像ができなかったかなって。
The more that I thought about it, the more I cried, and I couldn't imagine it happening.
しかも、そして、今でもできてないちょっと。
Honestly, even now, I still can't, really.
本当にわかる。
I know.
本当に明日からいないの？
Are you really not gonna be around from tomorrow?
いないなあ。
Yeah...
泣きそうかもね。泣きそう
Seems so. I'm gonna cry...
でも、まあずっとクヨクヨしてたり元気なかったら、ココは何しとんねん！みたいな感じで怒って来ると思うし、
But... if I mope about it and be all sad, I know you'll just get mad like, "the hell you doin'!"
4期生が4人という形になっても、
The 4th Generation may look like it has four members from now on,
いつまでも4期生は5人で、
but there will always be five of us,
4期生としてトワは頑張っていこうと思います。
and I will continue to work hard as one of them.
大好きなココ、このライブを卒業しても遊ぼうね！
I love you so much, Coco, and I hope we can hang out after you graduate too.
ココの新しい道が明るくて幸せが満ちたものとなりますように。
I hope that the path along your new journey is sparkling with happiness and joy.
いつまでもずっとずっと願っております。
And I wish it stays that way forever and ever.
ありがとう。常闇トワより。
Thank you. From Tokoyami Towa.
うぅーっ！泣くわ！
Don't cry!
なんか色々考えたら、泣きそうになっちゃって、コミ分けたこと全く
I just started thinking about a bunch of stuff... It overwhelmed you.
お手紙をどうぞ。はい。ボロボロだ
Please have this letter. It's a bit messy.
ありがとう！
Thank you! It's a bit messy.
ないざ。ごめん。笑顔で最後までいたかったんだけど、
Sorry. I wanted to keep smiling until the end...
まっトワ様最初から最後まで泣きもしたぜ！
Since the very start, you always have and still do cry easily, Towa-sama.
本当だね。本当だね。いやあ本当に。ありがとう。
Yeah. Thank you. Yeah, really.
ありがとう。ありがとうございます。
Thank you for everything.
トワ様…… もっとね、あの
Towa-sama... I wanted...
いや本当にね、あの私も突然卒業、突然だったので、
Really, y'know, my graduation was sudden. It was so sudden.
はい。あの 一番、あのビービー泣い出たのは多分トワ様。そう、意外だね。ででも
And... I think the one who bawled the most was Towa-sama. But, you know,
ほらあのSwitchがさ、ココの手元に入り、そのSwitchで最後みんなでほら、あのマリオカートとかできたね。もうすごい、もうそれも思い出になってる。
we finally got a Switch in Coco's hands. And with it, we all got to play Mario Kart together in the end. That also became a great memory.
なってんね。なってんね。なってんね。
It did. Yeah.
ちゃんと思い出は作れたから悔いは無いかな。うん。
Since we were able to make those memories, I suppose I have no regrets.
ま、悔いって言っちゃうとねもっと遊びたいかったからさ。それはいっぱいあるから、今ね。それは考えないようにしよう。
Well, saying that, I really wanted to play with you guys more. So maybe I have a bunch of them! But let's not think about that.
ふふ、うん。はい。トワ様ありがとう。お互い大事にしよう。ココちゃんありがとう。大切にするよ。
Okay. Towa-sama, thank you. Thank you, Cocochi! I'll treasure your letter.
うん。一緒に…… ま、卒業した後も遊ぼうや！うん、うん、遊ぼう！
Okay! Let's... Well, let's all have more fun together after I graduate!
うん。いるいる、いるから地球にはもうちょっといようかな。よろしく。
Yeah! I'll still be here! I guess I'll hang around on Earth for a while longer.
ありがとう。うん。もうお前、カナタかお前、お前！
I look forward to it. Thank you. Now you, Kanata. You. You!
いやあ、初めてこんなね、手紙なんかココに書いてきましてよ。
This is the first time I've written a letter to you, Coco.
ふふ。ちょっとね、いっぱい書いたんですけど、読ませていただきたいと思います。
Yeah! I wrote a lot, so I'm going to read it now!
うん。え、ココへ。とうとうこの日が来ました。すごく寂しいです。
Dear Coco, The day has finally come. It's a very sad feeling.
ココと出会って、同期として、仲間として、友達として、家族として、
I've spent a year and a half with you as my genmate, my colleague, my friend...
過ごしても、1年半だったね。
and my family. In the beginning,
最初ココがもうスピードで僕たちの前を走っていった時、
when you blew past the rest of us at super speed,
その背中に憧れたし、尊敬しました。
I really admired you and wanted to be like you.
本当に1人で圧倒的で、同期として並ぶのが怖いとか、萎縮すうにもなりました。
You were in a league of your own, and i didn't know if I deserved to stand on equal footing with you.
でも、そんな才能に溢れたココが孤独にならないように、僕が同期が隣に立てるように必死で頑張らないといけないって思ったの、覚えています。
But I remember thinking that I had to work my tail off to be able to stand by that super-talented woman's side so I could make sure that she wouldn't be all alone.
最初は本当に僕は実力不足で、ココのおまけとかココにおんぶにだっことか言われまくったりしたし、実際その通りだと思っていました。
When I started, my skills were lacking, and people were saying "I was Coco's sidekick" or "just leeching off Coco," and I really believed that.
今はちゃんと隣に立てていると嬉しいです。
But if I'm able to stand by your side on my own merit now, that would make me really happy.
ココと一緒にいるのは本当に楽で、もう何年も一緒にいるような長年連れ添った夫婦のような感じがします。
Being with you is so comforting, it feels like we're an old married couple who've been together forever.
ココは僕の前ではうるさくて適当で下品でゲップもするけど、ファンの前ではたくさん私の話をしてくれていて、いつも嬉しかったよ。
When we're together, you're noisy, sloppy, crude, and you even burp! But I was always happy when you would talk so much about me in front of your fans.
実はめちゃめちゃチェックしてました。あんなふうに僕の話をしてくれることがなくなると思うと、すごくすごく寂しいです。
To be honest, I watched you a lot! When I think about how you won't be talking about me like that anymore, it makes me really sad.
デビューしてすぐ先輩を追い抜く勢いで盛り上げると突っ走る姿、ホロライブのみんなが大事になって守りたいものが増え
Since your debut, I've seen your drive to not be outdone by our predecessors... I've seen the kindness you showed everyone when hololive became really important to you...
みんなに優しさをくれた姿
and there was more to protect.
辛いことがあったとき 強がって平気のふりをしていたけど
I've seen you putting on a brave face and pretending everything was fine during the hard times,
本当は一人で悩んでいた姿
when in reality you were worrying about it alone.
ホロライブに活気をくれた姿 全部忘れられないよ
And I'll never forget any of that!
本当に 本当に よく頑張ったね
You did a really, really great job!
誰よりも大好きだ かなココは永遠だよ
I love you more than anyone! KanaCoco is forever!
これからもよろしくね
Let's keep it going!
今夜はハーゲンダッツを奢ってくれよな
And you're treating me to some Häagen-Dazs tonight, right?
お前が奢るんだろ！
You treat me!
お、ま、ん、じゅう
Oh, man...
ということで 僕もね 実は急いで書きました
Okay, done. I had to write all that in a rush, too.
ちょっと ちょっとねこんな
I-It looks pretty bad...
なんて言うんだろう きたねえな なんてごめんなさい そこですね
Damn, that's packed. Let me take this chance now.
みんな あの ホロライブのみんなにちょっと呼びかけをしまして、僕ちょっと寄せ書きをみんなに書いてもらいまして
I reached out to the other hololive members, and got them to write messages for you.
なっ！？
What?!
なのでちょっとちゃんと、ちゃんとしたものもねお渡ししたいと思います。
And now I'll hand the whole thing over.
本当に、あー！
Ahh!
本当に、本当にホロライブの皆さん、ありがとう。
It's seriously from all of hololive. Thank you so much for everything.
ここちゃ...
Cococha...
ここちゃ！
Cococha!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you all!
うれしなぎなのだ
These are tears of joy.
本当にありがとう！ありがとう！手紙私すの忘れた！
Thank you all! Oh, I forgot to hand you my letter!
大好きだよ！
Love you all!
みんな あの
So, uh...
泣かせんといてよ！
Don't make me cry, dammit!
あれなんだ泣かせたのはルナじゃ、ルナが無理やりあげたのだみんなが、ルナに無理やり！
Who made it wain in here after I livened things up?!
からしてたのに！
I thought I was all out of tears!
あのさあ
Well, um...
４期生の皆とはね あの、もう申し訳ないことをしたね、でも
I feel bad for putting you guys through this.
何がよ？
What do you mean?
えっ？もう、いやあ
Huh? I mean, uh...
卒業をね、まあ、ね、うそ、嘘することになったっていうことがだよ。
The fact that I'm graduating.
ねえ、そんなことないよ。
Don't feel bad.
そんなことないよ。
Yeah, don.
ずっと５人だから。
We'll always be five in spirit.
すごい、多分いっぱい、いっぱいすごい長い間考えて決めたことだと思うから
I know you spent a lot of time mulling over the decision.
私達はそれをいけないことだと思ってないし、ここが新しい道を進むっていうのも私達はすごい応援をするし
All of us think you're entitled to that decision, and we'll cheer you on in whatever you do next.
本当さっきも言ったけど、たたち、が、5人で4期生っていうことは絶対変わらないから
Also, like I said, the fact that there's five of us won't ever change.
寂しいけど、そう、なんかイベントがあった時とかはドラゴン席があるし
We'll leave a dragonsized seat open whenever there's an event and stuff.
ドラゴン席ある！
Dragonsized!
用意してくれるかい？用意してくれるでしょ
Of course we will!
じゃあちょっと、最前列でお辞儀させてくれよな
Cool! Then you'll see me looking all proud in the front row.
お辞儀は仕組むよ、見守ってくれよな
The proudest of onlookers. Do it, seriously. Watch over us.
みんな、あのホロライブでもこれ、残りじゃねえや、ホロライブに残って、あの、どこまでもね輝いていけると思っています。
I believe you guys will keep shining bright here in hololive.
まあ私はね、私は、あのホロライブからは、いなくなっちゃいますけど、まあ私はね多分、あのどこ行っても輝いちゃうんで
As for me, I'll be leaving hololive, but I know I'll shine bright wherever I go.
かっこいい！
Damn, you cool!
どこ行っても輝いちゃうから、つまずいた時はいつでも戻ってこいよ！
I'll shine no matter where I go! Feel free to come back if things go south.
そうだよね
Yeah.
じゃあ、あのYAGOOが死んだ頃に戻ってこいよ
Well, YAGOO will probably be dead by then.
YAGOOが死んだら連絡しような、YAGOOが死んだら連絡くれよ
Get in touch once he is. Let me know when he passes.
死なんくても連絡しようよ
Can we keep in touch even otherwise?!
本当だよ、びっくりしたわ
We should, huh?
まあね、また会えるさ
Well, we'll see each other again.
また会えるさ！会えるよ！会えるよ！
We'll see each other again! Yeah, we can!
誰よりも幸せでいてくれ！幸せだよ！
Please be happy. You deserve it more than anyone. I already am!
ありがとう、わため！
Thanks... Watame!
大丈夫、大丈夫
There, there.
あの、ほら笑顔でお別れだぞ
Let's say our goodbyes with a smile.
ね、この後もね、ライブもあるから、そうそう、ここからよここから
Mhmmm. We've got a show to put on. We're just getting started!
あの、あ、鼻拭いてください、鼻拭きます、ぐすぐしなのだ
So... Ack! Wipe your nose. Wipe your nose. Doing just that!
あの、えっと、みんなにはね、あの視聴者の皆さんと、応援してくれてたファンの皆さん、4期生をね、大好きでずっと応援してくれていたファンの皆さんもね、たくさんいると思うから
Um, well, to all my viewers, all my fans who've supported me, and 4th Gen fans who have loved and supported us... I'm sure there's a bunch of you.
そういったことがね、最後にね。
So yeah, at the very end here...
角巻わたみみたいにこんなんなんないように、
Don't let Watame happen to you guys.
そうね！
Yeah.
しょぼしょぼがおーにならないようにね。
Don't start ugly crying.
あの、派手に、うん、送り出して。
I want you all to send me off with a bang.
よし！送り出すぞー！
We'll do just that!
もりあがっていこー！おうー！
Let's get hype!
私のいないホロライブを頼んだぞ。
Take care of Hololive after I'm gone.
任せろ！任しとけ！めちゃくちゃ任しとけ！
You got it! We'll take good care of it!
大丈夫かな？私がいなくてホロライブ、え、大丈夫かな？
Is Hololive gonna be okay without me?
大丈夫だよ、みんながいるから大丈夫だよな？
Don't worry about it! It'll be fine with you guys, right?
大丈夫だー！まったくだよー！
Totally! Absolutely!
元気で！元気で！元気で！ずっと、しよ、おめでとうな。ばかぁ！
Be well! Live strong! You guys... be happy... Gah!
ありがとう、今日は来てくれて。
Thank you all for coming today.
ありがとう。
No, thank you.
手紙も一生大事にするぜ！
I'll treasure these letters forever!
飾ってね、絶対飾ってね。私頑張るぜ！
Good luck! Be the best! I'll do my best!
ありがとーーー！
Thank you!
ここから見せるぜ。
Be ready to lose your shit.
それでは、セカンドライブ本番！いくか！
Alright, let's start the second live! Here we go!
やーーー！
Yay!
同じ未来を 見 て い た い
I want to see the same future,
あの 夢 手 に し た い
and hold that dream in my hands.
それぞれ 違っ た ココロ で 走れ go
Running with our own unique hearts, go!
どこ を 見 て も 真っ暗 な 場所 に 芽生え て た
No matter where I looked, it was pitch dark,
ほんの 小さな 希望 に この 瞳 奪わ れ た
when these eyes were captivated by a tiny hope.
不安 で 揺れる 心 を 上手く チューニング し て
Tuning my shaky, anxious heart just right,
ほんの 小さな 勇気 を 振り絞っ て い た よ
I mustered up just a tiny bit of courage.
諦め の 文字 デリート し て 進む
Deleting my doubts and moving forward.
苦しい とき も もう 私は ひとり じゃ ない から
Even during tough times, I'm not alone anymore,
だから もっと 夢 追いかけ たい
so I want to chase my dreams even more!
ワクワク 止まら ない
My excitement won't stop,
想像 超え て く 世界 見せ て あげる
showing you a world beyond my imagination!
アクセス し て み たい
Let's log in and try it out,
後悔 なんて そう させ ない
because I won't allow any regrets!
それぞれ 違っ た ココロ で 走れ go
Running with our own unique hearts, go!
仮想 の 空 に 輝く 眩しい 想い は
The dazzling feelings shining in the virtual sky
見た こと の ない 光 を 現実 に 届ける よ
bring an unseen light into reality.
いつも 聞こえる エール は ここ に キャプチャー し て
Capturing the cheers I always hear,
また 新しい 光 を 探し たく なる よ
I grow eager to find a brand new light.
君の笑顔は 保存して 進む
Saving your smile to move forward.
悲しい とき に 見返す よ 力 が 湧く から
Looking back during sad times gives me strength,
胸 を 張っ て 夢 追いかけ たい 奇跡 の ストーリー
so I want to chase my dreams with my head held high—
奇跡 の ストーリー
a miraculous story.
一緒に 作ろう 終わらない夢を
Let's create an endless dream together.
誰一人欠かせない愛が舞ったこの世界
In this world of dancing love where nobody is left behind,
それぞれ違ったココロで彩れ
we color it with our own unique hearts.
悲しいときも寂しいときも信じ合えるものがある
Whether I'm sad or lonely, I have something to believe in,
忘れずにこの鼓動鳴らし続けたい
and I want to keep making this heartbeat echo on.
終わらない世界に溢れ出すよ笑顔達
Overflowing into an endless world of smiles,
憧れの舞台立ちたいらしく輝きたい
I want to stand on the stage of my dreams and shine brightly.
時に涙してまた笑い合いたい
Sometimes I'll cry, but then we'll smile together again.
同じ未来を見たい
I want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい 踏み出そう奇跡の一歩を
and take that first miraculous step forward!
息切らして夢追いかけたい
I want to chase my dreams with no time to breathe!
ワクワク止まらない
My excitement won't stop,
想像超えてく世界見せてあげる
showing you a world beyond my imagination!
アクセスしてみたい
Let's log in and try it out,
後悔なんてここにない
because there are no regrets here!
それぞれ違ったココロで作る world
Let's build a world with our own unique hearts!
同じ未来を見ていたい あの夢手にしたい
Wanna see the same future, want that dream in my hands
それぞれ違った心で走れ go!
Running with our different hearts, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
In a pitch-black place, a tiny hope sprouted
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
My eyes were stolen by that tiny hope
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning my trembling heart full of anxiety
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
Gathering up just a little bit of courage
はあ みんな
Haah, everyone!
アイドルソロで 初めて 一緒のステージに立てたのが嬉しい！
I'm so happy we could stand on stage together as solo idols for the first time!
初めて！歌った！はじめて！歌った！みんなで歌った！
For the first time! We sang together!
見せてみない、見せてみない、どれどれ
Let's see, let's see.
なるほどなるほど、あ、可愛い！
I see, I see. Ah, so cute!
可愛いのだ、可愛いのだ、可愛いのだ、うん
So cute, so cute, so cute, yeah.
ぺったんこじゃん
It's flat!
え、誰がぺったんこじゃん？誰がぺったんこじゃん？
Eh, who's flat? Who's flat?!
あの、ちょっと後ろのイラストが変わった、お？ってんですけど、これ
Um, the illustration in the back changed, oh? But wait, this...
一体...お？どなた？
What on earth... Oh? Who is this?
あ、これ、いや、マンマ、マンパパンからの、え、卒業プレゼント！
Ah, this, no, it's a graduation present from Man-mama, Man-papan!
めっちゃ可愛い！
Super cute!
ちょっとみんなのフタミになってるよ！
Everyone's mini-futami!
誰が風の魔法使いだ！誰だよこれちょっと！
Who's a wind wizard?! Who is this, seriously?!
バカにしてないよ、きみ！
We're not making fun of you, you!
誰？君、写真と違うね！
Who? You look different from your photos!
別人じゃねえのな？君違う人だよこれ！
Aren't you a different person? You're a different person!
まともな見つめる顔よ！
Give us a proper staring face!
いや、でも本当になんか旅立ちって感じでね、すごく なんか力強く回って
Well, but really, it feels like setting off on a journey, feeling so strong...
ママ、パパ、ありがとう！
Mama, Papa, thank you!
美味しい、すごい！
Delicious, amazing!
リズム、みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
ルナもいるみんないるみんな！
Luna's here too, everyone's here, everyone!
四期生もいる嬉しい！四期生ぜん！
4th gen is here too, I'm so happy! All 4th gen!
なんか、なんかいるけどおかしーの！
There's someone weird here!
え、なんか後ろにいるのになんかバケモノとあと...
Eh, there's someone in the back, a monster and...
バケモノいるな！
There's a monster!
あ、なんか、あ、なんかたつのこ色ももしかして一緒に来るの、お前らも！
Ah, is Tatsunoko color coming along too, you guys?!
お前たつのこ？
You guys are Tatsunoko?
あ、一緒に来るのか！
Ah, you're coming along!
一緒に行くか！一緒にいくか！
Let's go together! Let's go together!
旅立ちだね。新しく旅をしてくるよ、みんな、私は。
It's a journey. I'll go on a new journey, everyone, me.
うん、ねー。
Yeah, right.
つらい、やだのら、るなのやだのら！
Painful, I don't wanna, Luna doesn't wanna!
寂しいじゃん、まだみんなで...
It's lonely, we're still all together...
うん、まだみんなで一緒に歌える曲があるだろ？
Yeah, we still have songs we can sing together, right?
お、な、ちょ、か、ある、あるだろ？
Oh, right, wait, there are, right?
まだ、あるよ！せっかくアイドル賞でこんな可愛く...こんな可愛く...
There still are! Since we're in idol outfits looking so cute...
待って待って、私、お尻、お尻、お尻、お尻...
Wait wait, my hip, hip, hip, hip...
お尻のっち！お尻のっち！
Hip-nocchi! Hip-nocchi!
ちょっと、タイのね、タイを持つものはね、やっぱね
Hold on, those who hold Thai... wait, tail!
タイを持つものは...せっかく持ったんだから...
Those who hold a tail... since we got it...
持ち上げるな、くすぐるじゃん、くすぐるじゃん！
Don't lift it, it tickles, it tickles!
邪魔！お前じゃねえよ！
Get out of the way! Not you!
持ち上げるものは...
Things to lift...
ルナ、ルナ、可愛い、ルナも、ルナも、ルナ...
Luna, Luna, cute, Luna too, Luna too...
後ろの、一緒に...
In the back, together...
いや、でも、ルナもあるのな、ルナと、と、ね、やっぱ、ぺ...
No, but Luna has it too, with Luna and, you know, flat...
あ、膨らんでるの！もしかは1人大きいのをんでね！
Ah, it's puffy! Maybe one of them is big!
たまえ、たまえ、たまえ、まま、ま、ま！
Tamae, tamae, tamae, mama, ma, ma!
いいよ、見せとこうよ！
It's fine, let's show it off!
お？やっぱこれはインスですか？
Oh? Is this the 'inssu'?
見せとこうや！これが卒業するものの脇タイじゃ！
Let's show it! This is the graduation armpit tie!
匂いかいとき！匂いかいとき！
Smell it! Smell it!
匂いかいとき！やばい！
Smell it! Oh no!
酸っぱい！酸っぱい！
Sour! Sour!
酸っぱいじゃん、酸っぱいじゃん！
It's sour, it's sour!
酸っぱいっていうの、彼女は酸っぱいっていうか
She says it's sour, or rather she says...
かなちゃんは酸っぱいと言うからさ！
Kanata-chan says it's sour!
毎回毎回、毎回か！
Every single time!
ルナ、ルナ、私卒業するのな？
Luna, Luna, I'm graduating?
いやだのら、ずっとここにいるのら！
I don't wanna, stay here forever!
じゃあここにいるわ！あ、あ、まだ信じられてない、ここ...
Then I'll stay here! Ah, still can't believe it here...
じゃあここにいるわ！
Then I'm staying here!
まだみんなでいよう、ずっと！
Let's stay together with everyone forever!
じゃあここでいようぜ！
Then let's be here!
じゃあ私もここにい...
Then I'll stay here too...
ずるい！
Not fair!
ね、あの、もっと、もっとみんなでね、このアイドル衣装で可愛く歌いたいけど...
Hey, um, we wanted to sing more and more together in these cute idol outfits, but...
もう時間がね、もうなくなってきちゃったから、やんちゃたんね。
Time is running out, you mischievous ones.
みんなで、え、こうして歌うのは5人で、ね！
Singing together like this with the five of us, right!
次の曲で本当の、本当の、本当に最後に成りますが...
The next song will truly, truly, truly be our last, but...
次の曲はね、え、僕が本当に、あの、作らせていただいて、みんなに本当に歌っていただいた...
The next song, um, I really made it, and everyone sang it for me...
曲がありまして、奇跡結びと言う...
There's a song called 'Kiseki Musubi'...
ありがとうだよね！
Thank you so much!
ちょっとさっき泣いちゃったから、ちょっと！泣いちゃうだろ、もう！涙腺が馬鹿になってる！
I cried a little earlier, so... I'm gonna cry, my tear ducts are broken!
約束しようよ 僕らが出会えた奇跡
Let's make a promise, the miracle of us meeting,
忘れないように
So we'll never forget.
夢見たい鉄のウイング
Like a dream, an iron wing,
最終アニメみたいなハッピーなエンドになる彼方へと飛ぼう
Let's fly toward a happy ending like the final episode of an anime!
寝ぼけ眼擦って 今日は何をしようか
Rubbing my sleepy eyes, what shall we do today?
永遠に続く海を駆け抜ける
Running across the eternally continuing sea.
今はため息よりも勇気を
Now, more than sighs, let's have courage.
諦めるなんてないの ここで歌う
There's no giving up, singing right here.
僕らの声は聞こえてますか 君に届け
Can you hear our voices? Reaching you,
学校の友達じゃ きっとない出会いだった
An encounter we surely wouldn't have had as school friends.
画面の先の遥か遠くまで
Far beyond the other side of the screen,
ささやいた言葉も 誰かの笑顔になる
Even whispered words turn into someone's smile.
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ奇跡 キラキラ輝くステージに
Connecting stars with our own colors, a miraculous bond shining brightly on stage,
連れてくよ
I'll take you there.
泣いて笑って走って 毎日ジェットコースター
Crying, laughing, running, an everyday roller coaster,
ともに横転してお昼寝しよう
Together let's roll over and take a nap.
ちょっと自信ない時 コトリとデュエットして
When I'm a bit unsure, let's do a duet softly,
今日だけは泣いちゃうこと許してね
Please forgive me for crying just today.
未来の僕らのアルバム開く
Opening the album of our future selves,
傷ついた写真だって宝物だ
Even wounded photos are treasures.
僕らの愛が見えてますか 君に届け
Can you see our love? Reaching you,
過去も個性も性格も違うけれど
Though our pasts, individualities, and personalities are different,
弱気なときはまばたきひとつづり
When feeling weak, with just a blink,
もう一回 もう一回 絶対に諦めない
One more time, one more time, I'll never give up.
前の背中追う下手っぴな僕でも 君の隣に行きたくて走るの
Even as a clumsy me chasing the back ahead, I want to run to be right by your side.
誰にも言えずに描いた夢が たとえ叶わないとしても ボロボロの靴でもかっこよくなくても
Even if the dream I drew without telling anyone doesn't come true, even in tattered shoes and looking uncool,
幼いあの日の僕ならなんて言う 止まらないで
What would the young me of that day say? "Don't stop!"
初めて僕らが出会った日 まるで昨日みたいに思い出せるけど
The day we first met, I can remember it as if it were yesterday,
もういこうか 最後に今 重なる5人の奇跡 僕らの声は聞こえてますか 君に届け
Shall we go now? Lastly, the miracle of 5 people overlapping now. Can you hear our voices? Reaching you,
黒板のメッセージ 桜のカーテンくぐって
Passing through the chalkboard messages and cherry blossom curtains,
僕らの声を聴いて ずっとずっと 苦しい日 楽しい日 悲しい別の日も
Listen to our voices, on and on, through painful days, happy days, and sad parting days,
それぞれの色で 星結ぶ奇跡 キラキラ輝くステージで 約束しよう
Connecting stars with our own colors, a miraculous bond on a sparkling stage, let's promise,
いつかここで また会おう
Let's meet here again someday.
みんなで歌えてすごい嬉しい
I'm so happy we could all sing together!
やったー！
Yay!
愛されてるわ
She's so loved.
愛してんで！ みんな愛してんで！
I love you! Everyone, I love you!
やっぱ4期生のね、この曲…カウタが、カウタがね…ねぼがきっかけですけど
As for the 4th gen's song... Kauta, Kauta... well Nabo started it, but
ちょっとね、自腹で、自腹でね、作らせていただいて
We paid out of pocket to make it...
本当にみんなにね、歌ってもらって…神曲、すごい嬉しい、ありがとう
And having everyone sing it... such a god song, I'm so happy, thank you!
神曲だ！神曲だ！
A god song! A god song!
本当にね、この卒業ライブの日に間に合うように、この時歌えるようにと思ってね
To make it in time for this graduation live and be able to sing it this time...
これで最後でもいいと思ってね、作ったんで
I made it thinking even if it's the last time...
あ、あの、ちょっと言いたいことあるんですけど
Ah, um, I have something I want to say...
なんかさ、カウタが配信とかでも「これで最後でもいい」って言ってましたけど
Kauta said in streams and stuff, "Even if it's the last time", but
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
この曲できればね？
If possible with this song?
うん、4期生みんなでね、また、私がいなくてもね、歌ってほしいと
Yeah, I want all 4th gen to sing it again, even without me.
って思ってんだよな？
That's what you think, right?
歌いたいしか！
I want to sing it!
いや、歌うしかない！
No, we have no choice but to sing it!
まだこの先のパートをね？
And for the rest of the parts?
そう、そう、みんなでね、歌ってもらって
Right, right, having everyone sing it...
まあ、ちょっとね、まあ4人、ま、パートがね、ちょっと分かれてるから
Well, since the four parts are split up...
私のパート…名前も入ってほしいな！名前も！
My part... I want my name in it too!
ま、でも、あの…
Well, you know...
みんなでね、あの、せっかく作って、私も大好きな曲なんで、あの、みんながね、あの、残り4人になっても歌ってんの、私は聴きたいよ！
Well, everyone made it together, and since it's my favorite song, I want all four of you who are left to sing it! I want to hear it!
歌おう！ココが言うならさ、みんなでさ、ね、ココの意思を継いで歌っていこう！歌っていこう！
Sing it! Let's sing it together, just like Coco said! Let's sing it together!
ありがとう！元気出そうよ！
Thank you! Let's cheer up!
クロガネだ、歌う歌う…！
Kurogane, let's sing, sing, sing!
あ、ちょっとこれ…これちょっと…あれ？ん？これ？あれ？ちょっと待って、なんか懐かしいね、この並び
Wait, wait, wait, wait, this... wait, is this?
なんか懐かしくない？この並び。なんか、あ、ちょっとTwitterのヘッダーにしてる画像だ！
Something doesn't feel nostalgic? This wave...
前にちょっと写真撮ったよね。
Wait, earlier we took a photo, right?
ちょっとできるんじゃない？これ再現しちゃって、みんな！
Can we recreate it? Let's try recreating it!
吸い込まれる！あれ？そうだ、座れ。
Suck it in! Alright, sit down.
僕たちのね、顔をね、横に並べると、身長差で実はこうなっているっていう写真です。
If you line our faces up horizontally, because of our heights, it actually ends up like this... it's a photo!
ももちゅんが、ももちゅんが…
Momo-chan's, Momo-chan's...
懐かしいな！懐かしい！
Nostalgic! So nostalgic!
いやこれで終わりなの？ゲブ秒でこれ写真撮って私緊張してたんだよなー！足震えてる、足震えてる足が！
Wait, is this really the end? We're taking the last photo and I was so nervous!
ブルブル、ブルブル足が…
Shivering, shivering!
これやりたかったんだよ最後に！やったー！
I wanted to do this at the very end! Yay!
いて、いて、いて…ダメージが！
Ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch! That hurts!
最初こうやってね、バランス取るの意外と大変なんだし。
If you kneel down at first, maintaining balance is actually pretty hard.
確かにね。
True!
いやー、めっ、や、これやりたかったんですよ！忘れんとこだった、やってよかった。
Yeah, I really wanted to do this! I almost forgot, but I'm glad we did it!
やりたかったんだよ！やりたかった！
Yeah, I wanted to do it!
え、ちょっと待って一つ思い出したんだけどさ、あのさ、トワたちさ、3Dになったらさ、ん？
Wait, I just remembered one thing. You know how when we become 3D...
プロレスするって言ってなかったっけ？
Didn't you say you'd do pro-wrestling?
プロレス！
Pro-wrestling!
言ってたな！言ってたわ、私、覚えてるの。
You said that! I remember!
全員でやるか？やったぞ！やるか？
Shall we all do it? Shall we do it?
ちょっとゴング鳴らないと戦えないから。
Wait, if we go too hard we can't fight!
ちょっと甘いな！
Too sweet!
やろう、やろう！
Let's go, let's go!
おい！
Hey, hey!
ココがやられている！
Coco is getting beaten up!
ココ愛！
Coco-ai!
やめろ！
Stop it!
お前、あ、やっぱこっち…そっち強い！そっち強い！
Hey, wait, over there! Over there!
いいから、やれやれ！に、押しつぶされちゃう。
You're gonna get crushed!
息が吸い付いたわ。
My breath ran out!
ちょっとか弱いな。まだまだ、直してきなさい。
That's weak. Still, still, go fix your posture!
ふふゆ。
Fufuyu!
いやね、あの、そろそろ時間だよ、みんな。
Well then, it's about time, right everyone?
私をね…
As for me...
最後のステージが…ステージを、見せたい！桐生ココってアイドルだよね？
I want to show you my final stage! Kiryu Coco is an idol, right?
それは分からんけど…
That I don't know, but...
それは、その…出来のこと！アイドル最後ぐらいは！
That's... that's the idol at the very end!
最後ぐらいってなんだよ、ずっとだよ！
What do you mean, "the very end"? It's always like that!
ずっと、なってほしい！
Always be like that!
桐生ココのアイドルっぽいことやってよ！
Try doing the idol pose!
アイドルっぽいことやってよ。アイドル…
Idol... Do the idol pose!
新感覚アイドル！
That's a new sensation idol!
というわけでね、最後に、私のオリジナルソング、桐生ココオリジナルソングをね、みんな聞いてほしいです。
And that's why, finally, my original song, Kiryu Coco's original song, I want everyone to listen to it!
聴きたい！
Listen to it!
あ、移動しようぜ。ココ、ここだぞ、なんだよ。
Move footage! Coco, here we go!
そうだね、どうせ。
That's right, yeah.
私のステージに来いよ！
Let's go to my stage!
走って、走って！
Run, run, run!
待ってよ、みんな！
Wait, everyone!
足早いの
You're walking fast!
到着！
Arrival!
ここは私の桐生会のランウェイでございます！
This is the Kiryu-kai runway!
ここはね、桐生ここ。
And this is Kiryu Coco.
最後にアイドル見せちゃうぞ、ゾンビー！
Finally, I'll show you an idol, zombie!
みんな盛り上げてくれるかい？
Will you all hype me up?
盛り上げていこう！腕組もう、腕組もう！
Let's get hyped! Link arms, link arms!
最前列をやるよ！腕組み枯らすぜ！
Front row! Work those arms until they drop!
みんなすまんね！腕組み！
Sorry everyone! Arm linking!
最前列！限界を突破！
Front row! Break your limits!
私のオリジナルソング、Weather Hackers☆！
My original song, Weather Hackers☆!
負けそうなときは 勇気をあげるよ
When you're about to lose, I'll give you courage.
今日も 眩しい笑顔で☆
With a dazzling smile today too☆
Weather Hackers☆
初めて出会ったときのことを覚えていますか？
Do you remember the time we first met?
夢と希望あふれた目で
With eyes full of dreams and hope,
空の向こう いつも眺めていたよね
you were always gazing beyond the sky, weren't you?
きっと特別なものなんかいらないよ
Surely you don't need anything special;
前に進む 勇気があれば
as long as you have the courage to move forward.
君が今踏み出した 力強い一歩で
With that powerful first step you just took,
どんな天気も 晴れてゆくよ
any weather will clear up.
(飛ぶぞ～！ 1, 2, 3, Jump！！)
(Let's fly~! 1, 2, 3, Jump!!)
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
朝の光を浴びた みんなのハートに
Into everyone's hearts bathed in morning light,
元気を届けるんだ
I will deliver my energy!
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
夢へと走り出した みんなの心に
Into everyone's hearts running toward their dreams,
青空を届けるよ
I will deliver the blue sky!
負けそうなときは 勇気をあげるよ 今日も
When you're about to lose, I'll give you courage today too,
眩しい笑顔で☆
with a dazzling smile☆
少しだけ頑張ったら 足を止めて休んでね
After working hard for a bit, stop and rest,
ムダなことなんてないから 振り返れば全てが繋がってるよ
because nothing is wasted; looking back, it all connects.
輝いた想いを 遥かな風にのせて 自由な空 羽広げたら
Letting your shining feelings ride on a distant wind, spreading wings in the free sky,
「いつだって前向いて歩いていけばいい！」って 君の心も 晴れてゆくよ
saying "Just keep looking forward and walking!" your heart will clear up too.
(いくよ～！ 1, 2, 3, Jump！！)
(Here we go~! 1, 2, 3, Jump!!)
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
朝の光を浴びた みんなのハートに
Into everyone's hearts bathed in morning light,
元気を届けるんだ
I will deliver my energy!
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
夢へと走り出した みんなの心に
Into everyone's hearts running toward their dreams,
青空を届けるよ
I will deliver the blue sky!
疲れたときには 癒しをあげるよ
When you're tired, I'll give you comfort,
飛ぼう 広げた翼で☆
let's fly with spread wings☆
飛ぼう…
Flying high...
広げた翼で
With wings spread wide!
1, 2, 3, Jump!!
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
朝からガンギマッた
As you're trippin' in high spirits,
みんなのハートに
I'm gonna launch a raid on all your hearts!
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
シノギで疲れ果てた
If you're tired of the grind,
みんなのケツから気合を叩き込むよ
I'll give you a dose of motivation right up your arse!
空に煌めく雷光
Lightning flashes up above,
響きわたった咆哮
our roars echo all around.
未来に輝く栄光
Glory rests at our fingertips!
その夢を諦めるな
So don't give up on your dreams.
こんなん理不尽も上等
Bring on all the trials and tribulations,
まとめて跳ね返す眼光
stare 'em dead in the eye and let the sparks fly!
Go your own way!
進め Right now!
Keep going right now!
まだ見ぬ 空の向こうへ
Toward the sky yet unseen...
Good morning, Weather Hackers☆
朝の光を浴びた
As you're trippin' in high spirits,
みんなのハートに元気を届けるんだ
I'm gonna launch a raid on all your hearts!
泣きそうなときは 元気をあげるよ
When you're about to cry, I'll give you energy.
行こう 素敵なスマイルで☆
So let's go, wearing a cute as heck smile☆